Welcome back everyone.
欢迎大家回来。
Next item on the agenda, session four, on.
下一个议程项目，第四场会议开始。
And we have three talks in that session and
该场会议中我们有三个演讲，
it will be shared by Tamer Refaei from Miter.
它将由来自Miter的Tamer Refaei分享。
Tamer, the floor is yours.
Tamer，轮到你发言了。
>> All right, so can you all hear me?
>> 好的，那你们都能听到我说话吗？
>> Yep.
>> 是的。
>> All right, nice.
>> 好的，很好。
So this is a DARPA Share program.
这是一个DARPA共享项目。
It's a very exciting program.
这是一个非常令人兴奋的项目。
I'm happy to chair this session.
我很高兴主持这个会议。
I think the DARPA chair program started about three years ago and
我认为DARPA主席计划大约在三年前开始的，
it's one of the duty programs that we leverage is Indiana's as the core network
它是我们利用的责任计划之一，以印第安纳州作为核心网络。
consolidate technology for addressing some of the limitations and duty many networks.
整合技术以解决许多网络的一些限制和责任。
So we're here to talk about DARPA Share.
所以我们在这里讨论DARPA Share。
We have three talks.
我们有三场演讲。
The first is from Dr. Mary Schurgot.
第一场是由玛丽·舒尔戈特博士主讲的。
She is the program manager for the DARPA Share program.
她是DARPA Share项目的项目经理。
So let me just tell you a little bit of a brief about Dr. Schurgot.
那么我就简单介绍一下Schurgot博士。
She joined DARPA in March 2020 as a program manager in this
她于2020年3月加入DARPA，成为该机构的项目经理。
strategic technology office, which is STO.
战略技术办公室，即STO。
Her research interests include secure and efficient data sharing, automated
她的研究兴趣包括安全高效的数据共享、自动化
decision aids and the design of new networking and communication paradigms.
决策辅助和新型网络与通信范式的设计。
Prior to DARPA, Dr. Schurgot was the technical director of machine learning and
在加入DARPA之前，Schurgot博士是机器学习的技术总监，以及
edge capability to Khaki, previously LGs innovations where she developed and
在此之前，她在LG的创新部门开发并提升了Khaki的边缘计算能力，
led programs at the intersection of analytics cyber and networking.
在分析学、网络安全和网络交互领域领导了多个项目。
Dr. Schurgot the floor is all yours.
舍戈特博士，现在轮到你发言了。
>> Thank you Tamar, and you can hear me all all set.
>> 谢谢你，塔玛尔，你们都能听到我，一切准备就绪。
>> All good here.
>> 这边都很好。
>> Okay, great.
>> 好的，太棒了。
Okay, and hopefully everyone can see my screen.
好的，希望大家都能看到我的屏幕。
Thank you, NIST for hosting this community meeting.
谢谢NIST主办这次社区会议。
I'm very happy to be here.
我很高兴能来到这里。
I'll give an introduction to the share program and
我将会介绍股份计划并且
then the remainder of the two talks will really get into the details about how
然后接下来的两场演讲将会深入讨论关于如何
we're leveraging NDN within share.
我们正在SHARE中利用NDN。
Okay, so SHARE as the name kind of implies is about secure data sharing at
好的，所以SHARE，顾名思义，是关于在多个安全级别的战术网络中进行安全数据共享。
multiple security levels within tactical networks.
在战术网络中的多个安全级别。
We have three focus areas in SHARE and I'll briefly touch on each of those, but
我们在SHARE中有三个重点领域，我将简要介绍每一个，但是
it's really the resilient networking piece that I think this
我认为这确实是弹性网络部分。
audience will be most interested in.
观众最感兴趣的。
Within SHARE we integrate with the tactical assault kit application to
在SHARE中，我们与战术突击套件应用程序集成以
demonstrate SHARE'S capabilities.
展示SHARE的能力。
Again, not spending too much time on the overall construct of the program,
再次强调，我们不会在程序的整体构造上花费太多时间，
but just to give you a feel for what we're doing here.
但只是为了让你感受一下我们在这里做的事情。
So SHARE is about bringing data sharing to the tactical edge where in contrast
所以SHARE项目是关于将数据共享带到战术边缘，在这一点上与传统方式形成对比，
the way that it's done today is to reach back
这种方式就是今天所采用的回溯方法。
to enterprise systems to be able to access data at multiple sensitivity levels.
连接到企业系统以便能够访问多个敏感级别的数据。
One of the challenges with that is of course, maintaining a VPN or
在战术边缘环境中维护一个虚拟专用网络连接。
Additionally, to be able to configure these systems can take on the order of
此外，配置这些系统可能需要花费几个月到几年的时间。
months to years.
几个月到几年。
In contrast, addresses those challenges by bringing data sharing within a mobile,
相比之下，通过在移动设备上实现数据共享来应对这些挑战，
handheld or basically an Android phone.
手持设备，或者基本上是一部安卓手机。
We can isolate data at different sensitivity levels within
我们可以在不同的安全区域内隔离不同敏感级别的数据。
different secure enclaves within the handset.
在手机内部设置不同的安全区域。
We address resilient networking using named data networking.
我们通过命名数据网络解决弹性网络问题。
So, we have caching and
因此，我们有了缓存和
synchronization within the network, rather than reaching back to a specific server.
因此，我们有了缓存和网络内的同步，而不是回到特定的服务器。Back at an enterprise system.
Back at an enterprise system.
回到企业系统。
And then lastly we have configuration management software that takes
最后，我们有配置管理软件，它可以
configuration time, down from months down to on the order of minutes.
配置时间从几个月缩短到大约几分钟。
So the the key piece to SHARE is being able to save data and
因此，SHARE的关键部分是能够保存数据并且使用增强的数据集。
store data with enhanced sets.
存储带有增强数据集的数据。
So here's a notional high level architecture
这里是一个概念性的高层架构。
of the SHARE system residing on a handheld device.
这是位于手持设备上的SHARE系统。
Here we have three notional sensitivity levels.
这里我们有三个假想的敏感性等级。
A medical enclave, a US enclave and a partner enclave.
一个医疗飞地、一个美国飞地和一个合作伙伴飞地。
All of those enclaves are managed within the phone through the management
所有这些飞地都通过手机内的管理进行管理。
enclave responsible for key storage, enforcing sharing policies and
负责密钥存储、执行共享策略的飞地，
then you can see they're coming off of the phones we have doubling encrypted and
然后你会看到它们从我们的手机上发出，我们使用了双重加密，
gn packets Of course to this audience,
然后你会看到它们从我们的手机上发出，我们使用了双重加密，数据包当然是对这个听众来说，
I really don't need to motivate the need for named data networking but
我真的不需要强调命名数据网络需求的必要性，但是
I'll emphasize that within a tactical or Gog environment.
我会强调，在战术环境或Gog环境中。
The mobility and dynamics are quite severe.
机动性和动态性非常剧烈。
To be able to maintain a persistent connection between a client and
要能够在客户端和
server is very challenging.
要能够在客户端和服务器之间进行有效通信是非常具有挑战性的。
And, that's what's meant by those dashed lines to represent intermittent links.
这就是那些虚线代表间死连接的意思。
Rather, with NDN in the SHARE program, we've demonstrated that we can not only
反而，在SHARE计划中应用NDN，我们已经证明我们不仅可以
be securely more data at different sensitivity levels within the handsets,
通过在手持设备中对不同敏感级别的数据进行安全管理，
but we can further enable resilient networking through the improvements and
但我们可以通过改进和提高我们对NDN（命名数据网络）所做的进步，进一步实现韧性网络。
advancements that we've made to NDN.
我们对NDN所做的进步。
Which again,
这再一次，
the next speakers will go into more details on those specific enhancements.
下一位发言者将会详细介绍这些具体的增强功能。
Some things that we've had to do,
我们不得不做的一些事情包括：
just to give you a brief introduction to adapt NDN for tactical use.
只是简要介绍一下如何适应战术使用NDN。
Starting with this diagram on the right side of the screen,
从屏幕右侧的这张图表开始，
we implement a NDN or
我们实现了一个NDN或者
we we store the NDN packets, data within the handhelds.
我们将NDN数据包存储在手持设备中。
We have different bridges and routers within the system.
我们系统内部有不同的桥接器和路由器。
And additionally, we are able to connect and
我们还能够连接并且~!@#$%^&*()
bridge [INAUDIBLE] enabled phones with NDN to non NDN networks.
桥接功能使得支持NDN的手机能够与非NDN网络连接。
And that's what you see there at the bottom right.
这就是你在右下角看到的内容。
We can connect share enabled
我们可以连接共享启用
tactical assault kit clients with just stat clients not running NDN.
可以将战术突击工具包客户端与仅运行静态客户端的NDN连接起来。
Little later on the slide you can see that we've
稍后在幻灯片上您可以看到我们已经
tailored some of the data synchronization techniques for this dynamic environment.
为了适应这种动态环境，我们定制了一些数据同步技术。
So In later talks, you'll hear more about the ICT sink that we've employed,
所以在后续的讨论中，您将会听到更多关于我们所采用的ICT汇聚点的信息。
as well as the additional improvements that we've made on the NDN side.
以及我们在NDN方面所做的额外改进。
This is kind of just a recap.
这其实只是一个总结。
summarizes the different things that we've done to the available
总结了我们对现有情况所做的不同改动。
NDN code base to make it work for tactical comms.
将NDN代码库修改使其适用于战术通信。
Most specifically, I mentioned the the different synchronization.
我特别提到了不同的同步方式。
Another thing that we've done relates to
我们所做的另一件事情涉及到
broadcast so rather than we take a tiered approach to broadcasting traffic
我们采取分层方法来广播流量，以避免过度负荷网络，尤其是在非常动态的网络环境中。
both as not to overburden the network, particularly in a very dynamic network.
以免过度负担网络，尤其是在非常动态的网络环境中。
Then lastly given the single threaded NFT implementation,
为了应对单线程NFT实现，
we've implemented techniques to further load balance and
我们已经实施了技术手段来进一步实现负载均衡，以免过度拥堵网络中潜在的单一瓶颈点。
not bog down a potential single choke point within the network.
不会拖慢网络中潜在的单一瓶颈点。
I briefly mentioned we do have a configuration management software.
我简要提到过我们确实有配置管理软件。
And that's to ensure ease of deployment and ease of use by the end user.
这就是为了确保部署的便捷性和最终用户的易用性。
We recently held our testing evaluation event.
我们最近举办了测试评估活动。
As part of phase three, Temar mentioned that this is
作为第三阶段的一部分，Temar提到这是
the SHARE program has been going on for a number of years.
SHARE项目已经进行了好几年。
We are in the last the final phase of the program.
我们正处于该项目的最后阶段。
Back in July we went out to the field and
七月份的时候我们去了现场，
we had this notional view or this notional
我们有这种概念上的看法或者这种概念上的
diagram represents the experiments that we conducted in the field.
图表展示了我们在实地进行的实验。
And while we were out there we not only demonstrated the value of SHARE with NDN,
在我们外出的时候，我们不仅展示了SHARE与NDN结合使用的价值，
but then we took SHARE off of the phones that we had out on the network and
但后来我们将SHARE从我们在网络上使用的手机上取下来，
just ran a stock implementation without SHARE.
我们只是运行了一个不带SHARE的标准实现。
And of course you didn't get the benefits of that caching and
当然，你也没有获得那种缓存带来的好处。
synchronization given to you within the SHARE NDN implementation.
同步功能已在SHARE NDN实现中为您提供。
There's also another effort going on within the SHARE program to
SHARE项目内还有另一个努力正在进行中，以
look at marrying SHARE capabilities with 5G technology.
探索将SHARE项目能力与5G技术结合起来。
More specifically, looking at how we can further isolate
更具体地来说，研究我们如何能进一步隔离
data at different sensitivity levels using network slicing.
数据在不同敏感性级别上使用网络分片技术进行隔离。
And that's a very exciting effort that DARPA has jointly with
这是一个非常令人兴奋的项目，DARPA与国防部研究与工程副部长办公室联合进行。
the Office of the Undersecretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.
国防部研究与工程副部长办公室。
And we have some demonstrations coming up in the new fiscal year
我们在新的财政年度有一些演示即将举行。
to show that capability.
展示这种能力。
And I just like to finish up and
我只想结束并且~!@#$%^&*()
kinda just give you a sense of the impact of SHARE.
有点像是给你展示SHARE影响力的一种方式。
So with each DARPA program, the goal is really to transition the technology and
那么对于每个DARPA项目来说，真正的目标是要将技术转化并应用到实际中。
the capabilities coming out of the DARPA program.
DARPA项目所产生的能力。
So we have great partnerships with a number of transition partners within
我们与许多过渡合作伙伴建立了良好的伙伴关系，这些合作伙伴位于
the tactical edge community, specifically the 75th Ranger Regiment
战术边缘社区，特别是第75游骑兵团
as well as the Telemedicine and Advanced Technology Research Center.
以及远程医疗和先进技术研究中心。
We have been tailoring SHARE to their use cases.
我们一直在根据他们的使用案例定制SHARE。
And of course name data networking,
当然，还有命名数据网络，
providing that resilient networking is at the core of those efforts.
提供弹性网络是这些努力的核心。
This is a NIST meeting, and thanks to Lotfy for
这是一个NIST会议，感谢Lotfy因为
working with us, and we're continuing to drive to ensure this compatibility
与我们合作，我们将继续推动以确保这种兼容性。
of NDN across government, industry, and academic or academia use cases.
在政府、工业和学术界的使用案例中，对NDN的潜力感到特别兴奋。
We're specifically very excited about the potential for public safety use
我们特别对公共安全使用的潜力感到兴奋。
cases as well, in addition to the military use cases that we've demonstrated today.
我们今天展示的除了军事用例之外，还有其他情况也同样适用。
With that, I'll turn it back to you, Tamer.
接下来，我将话筒交回给你，塔默。
>> Thank you, Dr. Schurgot.
谢谢你，舒尔格特博士。
Exactly in time, that's impressive.
恰到好处，真令人印象深刻。
So let's see, I think we have time for questions.
那么我们看看，我认为我们有时间来回答问题。
I don't see any hands raised.
我没有看到有人举手。
Does anybody have any questions?
有谁有问题吗？
>> I can probably ask a quick one.
>> 我可能会快速问一个问题。
What is the status of the program, and what are the next steps?
程序的状态如何，下一步是什么？
>> Sure, that's a great question.
当然，这是个好问题。
So that last slide that I presented was on SHARE transition.
所以我刚才展示的最后一张幻灯片是关于SHARE过渡的。
So we're towards the end of the program now.
所以我们现在接近节目的尾声了。
We have a lot of the underlying capabilities developed,
我们已经开发出了很多基础功能，
we have our system together.
我们的系统已经组建好了。
And now it's really customizing the SHARE solution to work with
现在真正的任务是定制SHARE解决方案，使其与
potential transition partners to make sure it's fitting for their use cases.
潜在的过渡伙伴确保它适合他们的使用案例。
We're really focused on customizing SHARE at this point.
我们现在真的很专注于定制SHARE。
>> Awesome, I have a quick one too.
太棒了，我这边也有一个简单的问题。
I mean, I think that the exercise that SHARE's doing is probably the closest we
我是说，我认为SHARE正在进行的练习可能是我们已经达到了一个基于NDN的可部署解决方案最接近的。
got to a fieldable NDN based solution.
我们已经得到了一个基于NDN的可部署解决方案。
It is great to have DARPA programs that consider NDN.
很高兴看到DARPA的项目考虑了NDN。
You see for
你看到了吗？在SHARE之后的NDN，其他DARPA项目也需要你考虑这项技术。
NDN after SHARE where other DARPA programs need you considering the technology.
SHARE之后的NDN，其他DARPA项目也需要你考虑这项技术。
>> No, thank you for asking that.
不，但还是谢谢你的提问。
Yeah, I think SHARE has kind of just scratched the surface on the value and
是的，我认为SHARE仅仅触及了价值的表面，以及
power of NDN to enable resilient networking within very dynamic
NDN的能力使得在非常动态的网络环境中实现弹性网络。
scenarios that align with DOD use cases.
符合国防部使用案例的情景。
And I think the 5G work that we're doing as well kind of speaks to that future.
我认为我们正在进行的5G工作也同样预示着这一未来。
Future of NBN particularly within DOD, but
未来的国家宽带网络特别是在国防部内部，但是在商业世界里也可能。
also potentially in the commercial world as well.
也可能在商业世界中。
>> Great, appreciate it.
>> 非常感谢，我很感激。
Thank you, Dr. Schurgot.
非常感谢，舒尔戈特博士。
So, moving on to our next speaker.
那么，让我们继续下一位演讲者。
Our next speaker is Constantin Serban.
我们下一位演讲者是康斯坦丁·瑟班。
He is a chief scientist at Perspecta Labs.
他是Perspecta Labs的首席科学家。
He is a CoPI on the Perspecta Labs DARPA SHARE very net program.
他是Perspecta Labs DARPA SHARE非常重要网络项目的共同首席研究员。
Constantin Serban has more than ten years of experience in network,
康斯坦丁·塞尔班在网络领域拥有十多年的经验，
especially focusing wireless networks,
尤其专注于无线网络，
network protocols, and security at all levels of the network stack.
网络协议以及网络堆栈各层的安全性。
Constantin, the floor is yours.
康斯坦丁，轮到你发言了。
>> Okay, great.
好的，太好了。
So today I'd like to talk about the PLI-Sync,
所以今天我想谈谈PLI-Sync，
which is a prefetch loss insensitive sync for NDN group streaming.
这是一种对于NDN群组流媒体的预取损失不敏感同步协议。
That's a sync protocol that we developed during the DARPA SHARE program,
这是我们在DARPA SHARE项目期间开发的一种同步协议，
and we develop it specifically for the conditions that Dr.
我们专门为Schurgot博士之前提到的，上一次演讲中的条件而开发它。
Schurgot was mentioning before, the previous talk.
Schurgot博士之前提到的，上一次演讲中的。
And this is joint work with,
这是与……的联合工作，
basically with our academic partners, Lan, Alex, and Lixia.
这是与我们的学术合作伙伴Lan、Alex和Lixia的联合工作，
And I'll just dive into the talk.
我将直接深入讲话的主题。
So the problem that we're trying to address here
我们在这里尝试解冑的问题是
is how to provide the group multi-party stream data transfer.
我们在这里尝试解冑的问题是如何提供群组多方流数据传输。
So we all know NDN is very good for
所以我们都知道NDN非常适合~!@#$%^&*()
serving static content or pre-generated content.
提供静态内容或预生成的内容。
Content that is generated ahead of time get served from various producers,
提供预先生成的内容，可以从不同的生产者那里获取，
and basically take advantage of all the caching capabilities
并且基本上利用了所有的缓存功能
of the network and interest aggregation for retrieving such content.
并且在检索此类内容时考虑了网络群组和兴趣聚合。
However, when we look at the group
然而，当我们观察群组
multi-party stream data transfers, we look at dynamic content production.
我们观察多方数据流传输时，会关注动态内容的生成。
So basically data that gets generated on the spot dynamically without sort of like
所以基本上是即时动态生成的数据，没有类似于
bulk generation where you have sort of like a big file or a big blob of data
批量生成，你有一种像是一个大文件或一个大数据块的东西
generated at once and then served piece by piece over a certain period of time.
一次性生成然后在一定时间内逐块提供服务。
And not only that the content gets produced dynamically,
而且内容是动态生成的，
but the data production interval might be stochastic.
但是数据生成的间隔可能是随机的。
You can view it as event driven rather than sort
您可以将其视为事件驱动而非排序。
of like periodic data production.
像定期数据生成这样的。
So that's the model of the application that we need to,
像定期数据生成这样的，基本上是我们需要解决的关键工具。
basically a key implement we need to address.
基本上是我们需要解决的关键工具。
And the goal of this work is not only to
而这项工作的目标不仅仅是要
provide the solution for such dynamic and stochastic data production,
提供针对这种动态和随机数据生成的解决方案，
but also to operate in disconnected
但也要在断开连接的情况下运行
intermittent link environments where the operating video reduce bandwidth.
间歇性连接环境中，操作视频需要减少带宽。
So which automatically demands very low overhead for the solution
因此这自然要求解决方案必须具有非常低的开销。
in low latency, relatively low latency, that's event-driven communication.
在低延迟，相对较低的延迟中，这就是事件驱动的通信。
And the timing of such transfers makes a big difference.
这种传输的时机会产生很大的差异。
And to the point basically operate on the network where the links go up and
这基本上是要在网络上操作，其中的连接时而建立时而中断。
down all the time you have frequent then permanent network party.
这基本上是要在网络上操作，其中的连接时而建立时而中断。如果你经常遇到网络部分或永久性的中断，那么你就会面对频繁的网络故障。
Can I be and what they mean network partitions or permanent or
这可能是指网络分区，无论是暂时的还是永久性的。
partitions it might be the general degenerate cases where
它可能是一般的退化情况，其中
the network is named never converges to have some sense and
它可能是一般的退化情况，其中网络被命名为永不收敛以具有某种意义，square network path available at any given time.
square network path available at any given time.
任何给定时间都可用的方形网络路径。
So you always have a subset of links.
所以你总是有一组子链接集合。
I'm basically down and the main cut might be zero of the network graph.
所以我基本上已经完成了，而且主要的割可能是网络图的零割。
So that's the type of problem that we're trying to solve in this environment.
所以这就是我们在这个环境中试图解决的问题类型。
So, and we focusing specifically on the on the sync protocol because
所以，我们特别关注同步协议是因为
usually event driven dynamic data production is solved by a sync protocol.
通常情况下，事件驱动的动态数据生产是通过同步协议来解决的。
And in the conventional sync protocol approach in MDM,
在MDM中传统的同步协议方法中，
you have Clear separation between the sync protocol and the data plane protocol.
你有同步协议和数据平面协议之间的清晰分离。
The sync protocol, basically producers notify
基本上，生产者通过同步协议通知消费者当数据通过同步协议产生时。
consumers when the data gets produced via the sync protocol.
消费者在数据通过同步协议生成时得到通知。
So the same protocol is As the role of notifying the consumers that the data
所以同样的协议就是用来通知消费者数据已经
got produced, and, of course, if you want low latency because things
已经生成，而且，当然，如果你想要低延迟因为事情
in the sink protocol needs to immediately notify the consumers.
在sink协议中需要立即通知消费者。
And then consumers in the data plane basically obtain the main data
然后数据平面中的消费者基本上获取主要数据。
from the same protocol and plus or fetch the data.
从同一协议中提取数据。
And the problem with this approach is that you have large overhead in the sense
而这种方法的问题在于，你会在某种意义上产生大量额外开销。
that you have to notify separately for each piece of data that gets you.
你必须为你获取的每一条数据单独发送通知。
Gets produce, you have to notify the consumer.
获取产品后，你必须通知消费者。
And in addition to that, basically transfer the data issue interest and
此外，基本上转移数据问题利益和
transfer the data.
转移数据。
And this is typically not a problem when you produce data in bulk and
这通常在你批量生产数据时不会成为问题。
the sync only applies to sort of like.
同步只适用于某种程度上类似的情况。
The notification over bulk data but
但是批量数据通知会
when you produce data piecemeal, the overhead becomes very
当你逐件生产数据时，开销会变得非常
significant and.
显著且。
Given those constraints and demands in mind, our proposal approach is to,
考虑到这些限制和需求，我们提出的方法是，
to use a hybrid approach a hybrid between the data plane and
采用一种数据平面和 控制平面之间的混合方法，
the same plane where we use optimistic content Content prefetching.
采用乐观内容预取的同一数据平面。
The data gets pre fetched optimistically,
采用乐观内容预取的方式，
using low latency and low overhead basically or no overhead and
采用低延迟和低开销，或者基本没有开销的方式，
in complemental users They vector based sync protocol
采用基于向量的同步协议来补充用户。
that fixes some of the problems that the optimistic
该方法修复了乐观策略中的一些问题。
content prefetching brings up and introduces a small,
内容预取引入了一个小的，
fixed overhead thing which is necessary in such networks.
固定开销是这种网络中必需的。
Moving to the next slide, basically our approach
转到下一张幻灯片，基本上我们的方法是
because of the optimistic prefetching and
由于乐观预取和
state vector sync protocol in the node model can be seen
节点模型中的状态向量同步协议可以被看到
bottom right of the figure physically an application.
图中右下角实际上是一个应用程序。
I mean a node consists of an application
我的意思是一个节点包含了一个应用程序。
ndn part basically the streaming, NDN application and
NDN部分基本上是流媒体，NDN应用程序和
the NFT And staying in the application consists itself
NFT及其在应用中的存在本身构成
of the part the sync protocol a consumer and
的部分同步协议一个消费者和
the producer, the consumer and the producers reside during the data plane.
生产者、消费者以及生产者在数据平面中驻留。
basically send interest receive Data,
基本上是发送兴趣包并接收数据包，
send it up to the application and sync plane is responsible for
负责将其发送至应用层和同步平面。
discovering of data production and
负责发现数据生成和
notification of, of data availability.
负责通知数据可用性的。
So in optimistic prefetching we adopt this team oriented
因此，在乐观预取中，我们采用了这种团队导向的方式。
namespace where the data is modeled as data my prefix producer identity,
在这个命名空间中，数据被建模为带有前缀的生产者身份的数据。
the identity and sequence number for each piece of data.
每条数据的身份和序列号。
Once the consumer has received a single piece of data
在消费者接收到一条数据后
optimistically shows an interest for the next sequence number and
积极地对下一个序列号表示出兴趣，并且
this is what we call optimistic prefetching.
这就是我们所说的乐观预取。
And basically before so this kind of interaction happens
这种互动发生之前
even before any seeing notification or in the absence of anything notification.
甚至在未收到任何通知或完全没有通知的情况下。
And before even the data has been produced, so an interest gets issued for
在数据产生之前，就发出了对其的关注。
the next data.
在数据产生之后。
To be produced or the next event to be generated by a by a producer.
生产者要生产的或者生产者要生成的下一个事件。
Given that the data is not the produce
考虑到数据并非生产物
we just periodically using a fixed and well known period.
我们只是定期地使用一个固定且众所周知的周期。
We need to use heuristic and learning methods for for setting the interest,
我们需要使用启发式和学习方法来设定兴趣，
lifetime So that's the data plane and optimistic prefetching approach and
我们需要使用启发式和学习方法来设定兴趣，这种乐观的预取方法即便没有任何同步协议也能工作得很好。
this optimistic prefetching approach works very well, even without any sync protocol.
这种乐观的预取方法即便没有任何同步协议也能工作得很好。
However, it has the problem of bootstrapping and
然而，它存在引导程序的问题，以及
operations in lossy environments.
在有损环境中的操作。
In order to address that problem, we use a state vector sync protocol that
为了解决这个问题，我们使用了一个状态向量同步协议，该协议在有损环境中的操作，supplements the optimistic prefetching and。
supplements the optimistic prefetching and.
补充了乐观预取技术。
State vector sync protocol produces
状态向量同步协议产生了
periodic interest based notifications over state vector.
定期基于状态向量的兴趣通知。
And the state vector contains the latest sequence number for each stream.
状态向量包含每个流的最新序列号。
For and for each User and that vector
对于每个用户，该向量
is produced by each node,regardless
对于每个节点生成的，不管它是否产生数据。
of whether it produces data or doesn't produce the data.
无论它是否产生数据。
Again the scope.
再次确定范围。
The purpose of this data state vector routing protocol is to
确定数据状态向量路由协议的目的是
provide bootstrapping and operations in lossy environments.
在丢包环境中提供引导和操作。
Moving to the next slide our to more details about our approach.
转到下一张幻灯片，我们将提供有关我们方法的更多细节。
And what's important for the operations of our paid
在我们的付费操作中重要的是
vector sync protocol is the fact that the state factor updates the state.
向量同步协议的事实在于状态因子更新了状态。
But the producer, but the consumer and the consumer and
但是生产者，以及消费者和消费者以及
the data plane and the consumer in the sink plane, and
数据平面以及汇聚层中的消费者，以及
update of the state vector in the consumer data plane is one of
消费者数据平面中状态向量的更新是其中之一
the components that has the biggest impact on our solutions and the shores.
影响我们解决方案和海岸的最大因素的组件。
At low latency of both data retrieval, so,
在数据检索的低延迟方面，所以，
the last two components especially the middle
特别是中间的那两个部件
vector state update represents the essential
向量状态更新代表了最关键的
factor in the performance of the PLI Sync so.
考虑到PLI同步的性能因素。
Rehash, the consumers fetch data eagerly.
重新组织，消费者急切地获取数据。
That ensures that data follows the eight vector propagation pattern.
这确保了数据遵循八向量传播模式。
Local NFDs of consumer nodes basically cache the data.
消费者节点的本地NFD基本上缓存了数据。
And PLI Sync enables hence the data fetching in disconnected network.
因此，PLI Sync允许在断开的网络中进行数据获取。
And put the figure to the right basically describes the functionality
并将图形放置在右侧基本上描述了功能。
in such a disconnected network where a node A, for
在这样一个断开连接的网络中，节点A，为了
example, produce the latest data produce is SQL number 15.
例如，生成最新数据的SQL命令是第15号。
Whenever it obtains some form of link connectivity with node B,
每当它与节点B建立某种形式的链接连接时，
node B gets notified of node A being sequence number 15.
节点B得知节点A的序列号为15。
And later on whenever node B gets in contact with node C,
并且之后每当节点B与节点C取得联系时，
it also notifies node C that A is at sequence 15.
它还会通知节点C，A处于序列15。
And the fact that nodes fetch data eagerly by the time node C
到节点C主动获取数据的时候
is notified about state, the same state of node A,
被通知关于状态，节点A相同的状态，
at that point it can also fetch the data directly from
在那时，它也可以直接从
the NFD cache content store of node B.
节点B的NFD缓存内容存储。
So that brings very robust operations.
所以这带来了非常稳健的运作。
To discuss some results.
讨论一些结果。
To the left, top left, the topology of the network where we
讨论一些结果。在左边，左上方，我们评估了这个网络拓扑的实施情况。
evaluated this implementation of
评估了这个实施情况
sort of repeatable environment.
某种程度上可重复的环境。
We run with it on natural physical phone in many scenarios,
我们在许多场景中在自然的物理手机上运行它，
in various situations.
在各种情况下。
For the results shown here is just the environment, the controlled environment.
在这里展示的结果仅仅是环境，是受控环境。
50 nodes in organizing 5 physical groups per access point.
50个节点分为每个接入点5个物理组。
Each node is both a producer and a consumer.
每个节点既是生产者也是消费者。
The links between each node and
每个节点之间的链接及
its own access point has 20% loss in uplink and downlink,
其自身的接入点在上行链路和下行链路中都有20%的丢包率，
so the loss is quite severe when you look at the end to end path.
所以当你观察端到端路径时，丢包率相当严重。
So in terms of metrics, we use overall interest to data ratio,
所以在度量标准方面，我们使用的是整体兴趣到数据比率，
data interest to data ratio, sync interest to data ratio,
数据兴趣与数据比率，同步兴趣与数据比率，
and overall efficiency and the- >> [INAUDIBLE] got a minute if you wanna
和整体效率以及- >> [听不清] 如果你想的话，有一分钟时间
leave time for the- >> You're right.
离开时间给- >> 你说得对。
>> Question.
>> 问题。
>> So just to highlight, the efficiency
>> 所以仅仅为了强调，效率
is very high when compared for example with the partial sync.
与部分同步相比，效率非常高。
And interest ratio, you can see 488 versus 188.
与利息比率相比，你可以看到488对比188。
And the biggest contribution is the consumer data plane contribution
与消费者数据平面的贡献相比，这是最大的贡献。
to the sync plane, as shown by the middle row in the table.
相比于同步平面，正如表格中间那一行所展示的。
And the lots of future works.
还有许多未来的工作。
Congestion control, asymmetric groups, predictability of production.
拥塞控制，非对称群组，生产的可预测性。
And thank you very much.
非常感谢你。
Looking for questions.
寻找问题。
>> Thank you Constantin.
>> 谢谢康斯坦丁。
Appreciate the presentation.
感谢这次演讲。
I think we have time for maybe one quick question.
我认为我们还有时间快速回答一个问题。
There's one in the chat that I'm just gonna read.
我将会读取聊天中的一个问题。
Could you explain very quickly if you don't mind,
当然可以，如果你不介意的话，请你快速解释一下。
how optimistic prefetch differs from adaptive pooling.
如何区分乐观预取与自适应池化。
>> There's a form of adaptive pooling.
>> 有一种自适应池化的形式。
You'll consume the data before the data gets produced.
你会在数据生成之前就消耗掉这些数据。
So in an adaptive, if you think about sort of like a congestion control
所以在一个自适应的情况下，如果你考虑的是类似于拥塞控制这样的情况，
algorithm where you adapt the rate of which you place interest,
算法会根据情况调整你的关注度。
you're adopted based on the network conditions here.
你是基于这里的网络条件被采纳的。
You adopt to when the data gets produced, so
你是在数据生成时就适应了，所以
you put an interest even before the data is produced,
你甚至在数据生成之前就表现出了兴趣，
you just wait for the for the producer to actually satisfy
你只需等待制作者实际上满足
the interest directly rather than for the network to satisfy or
你只需直接满足兴趣，而不是等待网络去满足或
the network to have the capacity of satisfying that interest.
你只需直接满足兴趣，而不是等待网络去满足那种兴趣。>> Okay, but that sounds good.
>> Okay, but that's sounds good.
好的，听起来不错。
So I think David asked a question in the chat, if you'd maybe try to follow up on
所以我认为大卫在聊天中提了一个问题，如果你可以尝试跟进一下。
the chat with him just to make sure that that sounds good.
所以我建议你跟他进行一次聊天，以确保这听起来不错。
So we're gonna move on to our next presentation.
所以我们将继续进行下一个演示。
Thanks Constantin, that was great.
谢谢康斯坦丁，那太棒了。
>> Yeah.
是的。
>> Our next presentation is coming from John DeHart.
>> 我们下一个报告将由约翰·德哈特进行。
John is a senior research scientist in the applied research lab
约翰是应用研究实验室的高级研究科学家。
at Washington University in Saint Louis.
他在圣路易斯的华盛顿大学从事网络原型研究和开发工作。
He has been working on network prototype research and development and
他一直致力于网络原型的研究与开发工作，
network test bed deployment and management for the past 31 years,
他过去31年一直致力于网络测试平台的部署和管理工作，
in addition to working as part of a Two Six Labs DARPA SHARE team.
他还是Two Six Labs DARPA SHARE团队的一部分。
He also currently manages the Open Network Lab at
他目前还管理着Open Network Lab。
Washington University St. Louis, and a global NDN test bed.
华盛顿大学圣路易斯分校，以及一个全球性的NDN测试平台。
The floor is yours, John.
轮到你了，约翰。
Go ahead.
继续吧。
>> All right, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
Okay, yeah, so as you said, I'm John DeHart from Washington University.
好的，是的，正如你所说，我是来自华盛顿大学的约翰·德哈特。
Standard disclaimer, this was all work was supported by DARPA, but
标准免责声明，所有这些工作都得到了DARPA的支持，但是
these are my views.
这些是我的观点。
Just a little background on why Wash U is is in this program.
只是简单介绍一下为什么华盛顿大学会参与这个项目。
It is because of the Open Network Lab.
这是因为开放网络实验室。
ONL is an Internet accessible network test bed that we built and operate.
ONL是一个我们构建并运营的可通过互联网访问的网络测试平台。
And with it we can do rapid emulation of a variety of network topologies and
通过它我们可以快速模拟各种网络拓扑结构和
conditions.
条件。
Including variable link bandwidth, link loss, delay, and so forth.
包括可变的链路带宽、链路丢失、延迟等等。
We started in 2016 on a seedling grant for
我们于2016年开始了一个种子基金项目，以支持
Joe Evans, where we used ONL to demonstrate how NDN
乔·埃文斯在那里我们使用了ONL来展示NDN是如何
could outperform IP and these challenging tactical conditions.
在这些具有挑战性的战术条件下，能够胜过IP。
Then starting in 2017, we began working on the DARPA SHARE
然后从2017年开始，我们开始参与DARPA SHARE项目的工作。
project as part of the team led by Two Six Labs.
项目作为Two Six Labs领导的团队的一部分。
This work focused on secure Android handheld devices
这项工作专注于安全的Android手持设备。
in these challenging tactical networks.
在这些具有挑战性的战术网络中。
The network challenges included low bandwidth links, lossy links,
网络挑战包括低带宽连接、丢包连接、
intermittent links, and temporarily segmented networks.
间歇性连接以及暂时性分段网络。
The focus of the program started out on Android over WiFi and
该项目最初的重点是通过WiFi在Android上进行。
cellular, and has recently shifted to using tactical radios
该项目最初的重点是通过WiFi在Android上进行，后来转向使用战术无线电。
with the Android phones connected through tactical radios in mesh networks.
将安卓手机通过战术无线电连接成网状网络。
The question again being could NDN provide more reliable transport
问题再次是，NDN是否能提供更可靠的传输方式？
than existing underlying networks for these tactical apps?
那么对于这些战术应用程序来说，NDN是否能提供比现有的底层网络更可靠的传输方式呢？
So just to give thanks out to the DARPA team, we've had three program
所以只是为了感谢DARPA团队，我们已经有了三位项目经理，分别是Joe Evans、Paul Zablocky，现在是Mary Schurgot。
managers starting with Joe Evans, Paul Zablocky, and now Mary Schurgot.
从Joe Evans、Paul Zablocky开始，到现在的Mary Schurgot，都是项目经理。
And their supporting cast have been great in supporting this program.
他们的支持团队在支持这个项目方面做得非常好。
Our prime contractor, Two Six Labs and
我们的主要承包商，Two Six Labs 和
many subcontractors, I just wanna highlight two entities there,
许多分包商，我只想强调其中的两个实体，
Two Six Labs and Eucleo have done the bulk of the NDN development.
Two Six Labs和Eucleo完成了大部分的NDN开发工作。
And our role as at Wash U has been done to do this scenario emulations.
我们在华盛顿大学的角色就是进行这种情景模拟。
And so I think this is a key point that kind of plays into the the panel from this
因此，我认为这是一个关键点，它在某种程度上与此次讨论小组的内容相关联。
morning in that we also have been a part of the Indian project team.
早上，我们也是印度项目团队的一部分。
We're not the ones doing the Indian development for this project.
我们并不是负责这个项目的印度开发工作。
It was these contractors who were doing it and that's a big step.
是这些承包商在做这个工作，这是一个重大的步骤。
I think for for NBN.
我认为对于国家宽带网络(NBN)来说。
So the the physical architecture that the shift we did from Android
所以我们从Android进行的转变的那个物理架构，
phones over Wi Fi and cellular to Android phones communicating
通过Wi-Fi和蜂窝网络到Android手机进行通信
through these tactical radios has created even harsher underlying
通过这些战术无线电设备造成了更为严酷的基础
network conditions than we had earlier in the program.
这些战术无线电设备造成了比我们项目早期更为严酷的网络条件。
In both cases, though, there has always been this condition of
在这两种情况下，总是存在着这样的状况，
the shifting conductivity as personnel carrying these these
在这两种情况下，总是存在着这样的状况，随着人员携带这些手机在现场移动，它们之间的导电性在变化。
phones out in the field or moving around that their conductivity to each other.
在现场移动的手机之间，它们的相互导电性在变化。
And these mesh networks is going to change and how How does our our applications and
这些网状网络将会发生变化，我们的应用程序又将如何适应这种变化呢？
our networking adapt to that?
我们的网络如何适应这种变化？
So MDN and DARPA share.
所以MDN和DARPA共享。
We are currently still using MDN 066 as our code base but
我们目前仍然使用MDN 066作为我们的代码基础，但是
we are considering an update to the current version.
我们正在考虑更新当前版本。
Some of the strengths of NDN that we have taken advantage of our sync,
我们利用的NDN的一些优势包括同步功能，
the strategy layer and the security model.
策略层和安全模型。
These have all been very important to achieving the success that we've had.
这些对于我们取得的成功都非常重要。
Initially, we did grumble some about the performance of NDN.
起初，我们确实对NDN的性能有些抱怨。
But that has become less of an issue as we've moved to.
但随着我们的转变，这已经不再是一个大问题。
Trying to use these low bandwidth networks with topologies on the order of 25 nodes.
尝试在大约25个节点的拓扑结构上使用这些低带宽网络。
The NDN modifications we have made have been kind of an evolution.
我们所做的NDN修改可以说是一种进化。
So we will find a cause for a network problem or
所以我们将找到网络问题的原因或者
an overload and then address it.
所以我们将找到网络问题的原因或者一个过载然后解决它。
And I was struck this morning again by the panel that that some of this you can think
今天早上我再次被那个小组击中了，你可以认为这其中的一些内容是...
of in lines of what Jeff Burke mentioned as the messy vitality approach.
在Jeff Burke提到的混乱活力方法方面。
That we as this program, not having to
我们作为这个项目，不需要
be in a maintain code base with the rest of the Indian project.
维护与印度项目其他部分的代码库。
We could make changes that we didn't have to worry about satisfying everybody else
我们可以做出改变，而不必担心满足其他所有人。
and so we could be a little messy and do what we wanted.
因此我们可以有点杂乱无章，做我们想做的事情。
And I'll discuss some of these modifications in the following slides.
我将在接下来的幻灯片中讨论其中的一些修改。
So ICT sync.
So ICT 同步。
It was developed by Hila van Abraham at Washington.
它是由华盛顿的希拉·范·亚伯拉罕开发的。
You, as part of her dissertation work,
她作为她博士论文工作的一部分，
it is a multi producer sync protocol that includes the participants
它是一个包含参与者的多生产者同步协议。
view of the state of the sync tree in the sync interest name.
它在同步兴趣名中查看同步树状态的视图。
So when a participant receives a sync interest,
所以当一个参与者收到一个同步兴趣时，
it can immediately tell From the Sync name in that interest,
它可以立刻从那个兴趣中的同步名称中得知，
how the state that somebody else sees of the tree compares to how it sees it and
它如何将其他人所看到的树的状态与自己所看到的进行比较，以及
know immediately if there is data new data out there that it needs to retrieve.
立即知道是否有新数据需要检索。
Clearly there is a potential name size scaling issue here.
显然，这里存在一个潜在的名称大小缩放问题。
But for the current scope of the work that we've been doing in DARPA share it has not
但就我们在DARPA共享的工作当前范围而言，它还没有
become a problem.
成为一个问题。
So it hasn't risen to the level that we felt like we needed to address that but
所以它还没有上升到我们觉得需要解决那个问题的程度，但是
it is out there for future work.
它是未来工作的内容。
So the next modification is local first multicast strategy.
因此，下一个修改是优先考虑本地的多播策略。
What we've found in these mesh topologies that multicast as the strategy for
在这些网状拓扑中我们发现，将多播作为策略来进行
the sync interest added a lot of traffic to the network.
同步兴趣增加了网络中的大量流量。
This is similar to what Constantine just talked about that that sync interest,
这和康斯坦丁刚才讨论的同步兴趣是类似的，
add a lot of data to the the network overload.
这会给网络增加很多数据，导致网络过载。
So we started working on ways to reduce that.
所以我们开始研究减少这种情况的方法。
And what we came up with is a strategy we call local first multicast.
我们提出了一种我们称之为本地优先多播的策略。
So in each of our nodes, there is an NFT and
因此，在我们的每一个节点中，都有一个NFT和
there's an application that that uses sync.
所以，在我们的每一个节点中，都有一个NFT和一个应用程序在使用同步。
And if an interest arrives at that NFT that a local face
如果一个兴趣到达了那个本地接口的NFT，
has registered a matching prefix for then the NFT will send only to that local face.
如果已经注册了一个匹配的前缀，那么NFT将只发送到那个本地接口。
If there is no matching local face for
如果没有匹配的本地接口，
the interest then it is multicast out to all the remote faces.
那么兴趣就会被多播到所有远程接口。
And interest from the local sync app
将会从本地同步应用中产生兴趣。
will always be multicast out to all the remote faces.
将始终被多播到所有远程接口。
And what this does is this gives the local sync app a chance to merge its state
这样做的目的是给本地同步应用程序一个机会来合并它的状态
with any incoming state before sending out a multicast to all the neighbors.
在发送多播给所有邻居之前，先与任何传入的状态合并。
So let's take a look on the next slide at how this has performed for us.
那么让我们看一下下一张幻灯片，它是如何为我们展现性能的。
So our test configuration here has 25 fully connected nodes.
那么我们这里的测试配置有25个完全连接的节点。
Each sync app will produce 100 chunks of data at five chunks per second.
每个同步应用将以每秒五个数据块的速度产生100个数据块的数据。
The charts at the bottom show the ol real time monitoring charts
底部的图表展示了实时监控图表。
which are displaying the instantaneous link bandwidth on our network.
它们显示了我们网络上的即时链接带宽。
The width of each of these pulses that you see is a way to quickly measure how long
这些你看到的每个脉冲的宽度是一种快速衡量多长时间的方法
it took for all the nodes to receive all the data The pulse widths for a very
对于一个非常成功的实验，所有节点接收所有数据所需的时间应该是大约20秒，对于我们发送的数据来说。
successful experiment should be about 20 seconds for the data that we were sending.
对于我们发送的数据来说，一个非常成功的实验，所有节点接收所有数据所需的时间应该是大约20秒。
And in these charts, we're comparing standard MDM with Sharon dn and
在这些图表中，我们比较的是标准MDM和Sharon dn。
also comparing the use of multicast versus local first multicast for sync.
在这些图表中，我们还比较了使用多播与首先本地多播进行同步的情况。
The data strategy for all these cases is multicast and
在所有这些情况下的数据策略是多播，
the link bandwidth is eight megabits per second.
链路带宽是每秒八兆比特。
So just from these charts, running these experiments on one hour we can easily see
从这些图表中我们可以清楚地看到，仅仅通过对一小时的实验数据分析，
the improvement we get from using local first multicast, But even with this,
我们从使用本地优先多播中获得的改进，但即便如此，
we are still bumping up against that eight megabit per second link raid.
我们仍然受限于那个每秒八兆比特的链路速度。
And so we're still dropping traffic and
因此我们仍然在丢失数据传输。
we still may have some latency issues for data retrieval.
因此我们在数据检索时可能仍会遇到一些延迟问题。
So the next thing we looked at then was to look at ways to reduce the network traffic
因此，我们接下来研究的是减少网络流量的方法。
on the data side.
在数据方面。
And so using multicast to all nodes in a 25 node mesh
会在一个25节点的网状网络中向所有节点使用多播
produces a lot of extra traffic.
产生了大量额外的流量。
So we looked at what would happen if we divided the nodes into overlapping
所以我们研究了如果将节点划分为重叠的
neighborhoods.
社区。
And here we have a range of one neighborhood of 25 nodes,
这里我们有一个包含25个节点的社区范围。
two neighborhoods of 13 nodes down to a daisy chain of
两个由13个节点组成的邻域直至一个雏菊链。
neighborhoods where each one has two nodes in it.
由两个节点组成的邻域。
And for this set of experiments I'm going to show you we have each node produce
对于这组实验，我将向您展示的是我们让每个节点产生
1000 chunks at five per second, and
在这组实验中，我将向您展示的是我们让每个节点产生1000个数据块，速度为每秒5个，而且连接速度再次限制为每秒八兆比特。
the links are again limited to eight megabits per second.
连接速度再次限制为每秒八兆比特。
On the next slide, the ol monitoring chart is monitoring the nodes that
在接下来的幻灯片中，ol监控图正在监控那些节点。
are color coded and these neighborhood diagrams.
在这些邻域图中，它们被编上了色码。
And for this set of experiments, we are pre configuring static neighborhoods,
对于这组实验，我们预先配置了静态的邻域。
which is not necessarily a realistic situation, but
这并不一定是一个现实的情况，但是
we'll address that in the next modification that we talked about.
我们会在我们谈论过的下一次修改中解决这个问题。
So again this is an ol monitoring chart for experiments run on topologies.
所以这又是一个用于在拓扑结构上运行实验的在线监控图表。
With different sides neighbourhoods,
具有不同边的邻域，
we have the 25 node neighbourhood on the far left, then 13, six, four and
我们在最左边有一个25个节点的邻域，然后是13个，6个，4个，以及
two node neighbourhoods off to the right for each experiment where you're using
我们在每个实验中向右侧有两个节点的邻域使用
local first multicast strategy for sync And multicast strategy for data.
本地首先使用多播策略进行同步，然后使用多播策略进行数据传输。
You can see that as we reduce the size of the neighborhoods as you would expect,
您可以看到，正如您所预期的那样，当我们减小邻域的大小时，
the traffic load decreases.
交通负载减少了。
>> We also see as you should expect that nodes that bridge
我们还看到，正如你所预期的，那些连接的节点
to neighborhoods have higher loads than the other nodes.
到邻居的节点比其他节点有更高的负载。
So this result led us to develop what we call random cast and strategies.
所以这个结果促使我们开发了我们所称的随机投递和策略。
So random cast N is a strategy for that we use for the data traffic.
所以随机投递N是我们用于数据流量的一种策略。
So we have nodes that have M faces where M is large,
所以我们有节点，它们有M个面，而M的数值很大，
multicast and broadcast regularly overloaded the network.
多播和广播经常使网络过载。
For each interest, what we wanna do is we wanna select N
对于每个兴趣点，我们想要做的是选择N个
random faces out of those M faces and multicast adjust those N.
从这M个面孔中随机选择N个面孔，并进行多播调整。
Typical ends that we have found that,that work well for
我们发现的典型的有效末端包括
us are in the three to five range.
我们发现的典型的有效末端包括us are in the three to five range. This has shown itself to be a very useful strategy for~!@#$%^&*()
This has shown itself to be a very useful strategy for
这已经证明是一个非常有用的策略，用于
the data traffic and is what's being used out in the field.
这已经证明是一个非常有用的策略，用于数据流量，并且是目前实际应用中所使用的。
Okay, persistent interest is an idea that's been floated around before.
好的，持续的兴趣是之前提出过的一个概念。
Philip Mole talked about it once and
菲利普·莫尔曾经谈论过这个话题，还有可能是其他人也研究过这个概念。
perhaps others have have looked at it.
或许其他人也研究过这个问题。
It's an experimental thing we're working with and it is of course,
这是我们正在研究的一个实验性事物，当然，
perhaps a bit controversial, because it does break the NDN flow balance principle.
可能有点争议，因为它确实打破了NDN流量平衡原则。
But again, this is a mechanism that we've been experimenting with to reduce
但是，这又是一个我们一直在试验的机制，用来减少
the overhead of interest for retrieving large data items like files or maps.
开销，用于检索大型数据项，如文件或地图。
So a persistent interest is a prefix,
所以持久性兴趣是一个前缀，
perhaps a file name without the sequencer or chunk numbers.
或许是一个没有序列号或块编号的文件名。
When an edit with an O survey.
It might be a file name without a serial number or block number. >> If that's of interest to you.
>> If that's of interest to you.
如果这对你有兴趣的话。
If you'd like to learn more about
如果你想了解更多关于
Python at this meeting [INAUDIBLE].
Python在这次会议上[无法听清]。
>> Okay, so when an NFD receives a persistent interest,
好的，所以当NFD收到一个持久性兴趣时，
if it has any data and the content store that matches it,
如果它有任何数据以及与之匹配的内容存储，
it returns all of that data.
它会返回所有这些数据。
The interest will then remain in the pit for its lifetime and
利息将在其生命周期内一直留在坑中，并且
continues to cause the return of any new data.
将持续导致任何新数据的返回。
If the persistent interest reaches all the way to the producer,
如果持久的兴趣一直延伸到生产者那里，
the producer responds with all its matching data.
生产者会响应其所有匹配的数据。
When the persistent interest times out at the consumer, the consumer can send
当持久兴趣在消费者处超时时，消费者可以发送
a new one with a last seen sequence number indicator or
一个带有最后一次看到的序列号指示器的新的
send individual non persistent interests for the missing sequence numbers.
发送针对丢失序列号的非持久性单独兴趣请求。
Okay, so in conclusion, DARPA SHARE has exercise NDN and
好的，总之，DARPA SHARE 已经对NDN进行了测试和
some new and very challenging ways, but
一些新的且非常具有挑战性的方式，但是
we feel like we have shown that NDN can perform successfully in these conditions.
我们觉得我们已经证明了NDN能够在这些条件下成功地执行任务。
We do plan to start feeding some of our code and modifications back into the NDN
我们确实计划开始将我们的一些代码和修改反馈到NDN的代码库中，在过渡的来年还有更多的工作要做。
code base, and there's still more work to do in the coming year of transition.
代码库中，而且在过渡的来年还有更多的工作要做。
So if we have time for a question, I am done.
所以如果我们还有时间提问的话，我就结束了。
>> Thanks John.
>> 谢谢约翰。
I think we're at a time, but just to be fair to all the speakers.
我认为我们时间差不多了，但为了对所有发言者公平。
Let's see if anybody has a question.
我们来看看有没有人有问题。
I see a lot of continent chat.
我看到很多关于大陆的聊天。
Does anybody have a question for John?
有谁对约翰有问题吗？
Or I'll throw one real quick.
或者我会迅速抛出一个问题。
Yes, to the notion of persistent interest is definitely controversial.
是的，对于持续兴趣的概念无疑是有争议的。
So how does that work with Ability.
那么，这是如何与能力相结合的呢？
>> It actually worked really well out in the field for for transferring files.
实际上，在野外传输文件时效果非常好。
And that's really what we use it for is if someone has a map or a picture or
实际上，我们使用它的目的就是如果有人有一张地图或者一张照片或者
something to transmit, you can send that one persistent interest and you don't.
实际上，如果有人有一张地图或者一张照片或者某些要传输的东西，你可以发送一个持续的兴趣，而不是不发送。
You don't typically get 100% of the data for that, but then the typical
通常情况下，你不会得到100%的数据，但是典型的做法是
approaches to then just send individual interests for the missing pieces and
尝试只对缺失的部分发送单独的兴趣请求。
it did greatly reduce the number of the amount of interest traffic.
它确实大大减少了兴趣流量的数量。
That was out there.
这真是太离谱了。
>> Thanks John.
>> 谢谢约翰。
Thanks to all the speakers, very exciting session.
感谢所有的发言者，这是一个非常激动人心的环节。
So I'll hand it off to look.
所以我将交给Look来处理。
Thank you all.
谢谢大家。
>> Okay, thanks Tamer.
好的，谢谢Tamer。
Next session is on IoT and Edge.
下一环节是关于物联网和边缘计算的。
Ken Calvert is a professor at University of Kentucky and
Ken Calvert 是肯塔基大学的一位教授，
he will chair this session.
他将主持这个会议。
>> Okay, thanks.
>> 好的，谢谢。
[COUGH] Yeah, my name is Ken Calvert and
是的，我叫Ken Calvert，
this session is titled IoT and Edge.
本次会议的主题是物联网和边缘计算。
But we really have quite a collected and diverse group of topics here.
但我们这里确实汇集了一系列多样化的主题。
I think it'll be very interesting.
我认为这将会非常有趣。
Our first speaker is Marie-Jose Montpetit and
我们的第一位演讲嘉宾是Marie-Jose Montpetit，
she's an adjunct professor at Concordia University, and
她是康考迪亚大学的兼职教授，并且
an advisor to to startups in the area of intelligent controllers.
她是智能控制器领域初创企业的顾问。
And her current research is in the architecture, design and
她目前的研究集中在架构、设计和
implementation of distributed intelligence systems in IoT using ICN principles and
实施分布式智能系统在物联网中使用ICN原则和
computing in the network.
在网络中计算。
She's co-chair of two IRTF working groups.
她是两个IRTF工作组的联合主席。
One a network coding and one in computing in the network or coin, and
她是网络编码和网络计算或COIN工作组的联合主席。
she's a member of the FlexNGIA community for Next Generation Internet services,
她是下一代互联网服务的FlexNGIA社区的成员，
and she's gonna talk about the decision maker.
她将会讲述关于决策者的话题。
So take it away Maria Jose.
那就由你来接手吧，Maria Jose。
>> Hi, I'm Marie and I think this is more of
>> 嗨，我是Marie，我认为这更像是一个概念，而不是一个完全成形的项目，就像
a concept again than a fully baked project like
一个概念，而不是一个完全成型的项目，就像
some of the other presentations earlier today.
一些其他的演讲是在今天早些时候进行的。
This actually came from do three years
这实际上来自于三年前。
now that I tried to see if we could do NDN and
现在我尝试看看我们是否能做NDN和
ICN inside real applications.
ICN在真实应用程序中。
So doing it from the bottom up instead of the top down.
所以是自下而上而不是自上而下地做这件事。
So starting from an application that people have and
所以从人们已有的应用程序开始，
trying to see what can we do with, what do they need and what is happening.
尝试着去看看我们能做什么，他们需要什么以及正在发生什么。
We're very lucky in the way and I'm going to talk
我们非常幸运，而且我接下来要讲的是
about that later that everything now is data driven.
关于那个稍后再说，现在的一切都是数据驱动的。
And this is especially true in the IoT world,
在物联网的世界里，这一点尤其正确，
which in that layered architecture used to be the data
在那个分层架构中，曾经是数据的部分。
acquisition layer you were acquiring your data.
在那个分层架构中，你负责获取数据的部分。
And you were essentially, because these things were used to be very,
而你基本上是因为这些东西过去通常是非常简单的，
the IoT, it was a bunch of very simple sensors with very little power and
物联网，它由一些非常简单、功率非常小的传感器组成，
the only way you could really make it work was to connect them
唯一能让它们正常工作的方法是将它们连接起来。
to some kind of gateway kind of dumb who was just sending
将它们连接到某种网关，这种网关相当简单，只负责发送数据。
everything to the cloud and everything was done there.
将一切都传送到云端，并且所有的事情都在那里完成。
Well, in the past few years, what we've seen is this data acquisition layer
在过去几年中，我们所见证的是这个数据获取层
now gives rise to a bunch of very, very different data sets.
现在催生了一系列非常非常不同的数据集。
I started looking at that in terms of the multimedia world, but it's more and
我开始从多媒体世界的角度考察这个问题，但它更多地涉及到工业领域。
more into industrial.
更多地涉及到工业领域。
We heard about automotive.
我们听说了有关汽车的事情。
I have a friend at Ford who's in charge of that connected car and
我有一个在福特的朋友，他负责那个联网汽车项目，还有联网汽车也会产生各种不同的数据集，
the connected car generates also all kinds of different data sets, and
联网汽车也会产生各种不同的数据集，以及
the problem is data sets or eternal genius.
问题在于数据集还是永恒的天才。
And so the bit rates go from, okay, I'm going to measure
那么比特率就从，好的，我将要测量
temperature once an hour and I'm going to have a few bits too.
温度我会每小时测量一次，我还会有一些数据位需要记录。
I'm going to take a complete time series of a bunch of pictures and
我将会连续拍摄一系列照片，
I'm going to afford with that generate a few hundred megabytes of information.
我将会产生几百兆字节的信息。
So what should I do?
那么我应该怎么办？
On top of it, there's a lot of this information that is time sensitive.
在此之上，还有很多这类信息是时间敏感的。
So I may not have time to go back all the way to my
所以我可能没有时间折回去我的
decision makers in the web or in the cloud to do that.
决策者需要在网络或云端进行这些操作。
But at the same time I need my cloud infrastructure to train my algorithms if
但与此同时，我需要我的云基础设施来训练我的算法，如果
I'm going to do intelligence systems.
我将要研究智能系统。
I need to know, and there we start looking at the link to NDN,
我需要了解，然后我们开始研究与NDN的联系。
I need to know which of that data I want to see.
我需要知道我想要查看哪些数据。
And in I here I am not talking of a person,
在这里我说的不是一个人，
I am talking of a controller, and I'm talking of a process.
我在这里所说的是一个控制者，我所说的是一个过程。
I am talking of an intelligent bot somewhere in the system that
我在这里所说的是系统中某个地方的一个智能机器人，它需要那些信息，不需要所有的信息，只需要其中的一部分。
needs that information, doesn't need all of it, needs part of it.
它需要那些信息，不需要所有的信息，只需要其中的一部分。
And all these sensors are essentially providing an answer to these questions.
这些传感器本质上是在为这些问题提供答案。
And obviously we're talking of sometimes very small systems,
显然我们在谈论的是有时非常小的系统，
so you may not want to reproduce all of the capabilities everywhere.
所以你可能不想在所有地方复制所有的功能。
You may wanna be able to borrow some of the capabilities from the next
你可能会想从隔壁借用一些功能。
door system if you can, or even, and I put the 5G broadband there.
门系统如果可以的话，或者甚至，我把5G宽带放在那里。
Because we've talked a lot to actually
因为我们实际上已经讨论了很多
the 5G providers in Canada about doing a project like that.
加拿大的5G服务提供商讨论了这样一个项目。
And how we could connect all these intelligent beings and
加拿大的5G服务提供商讨论了这样一个项目：我们如何能将所有这些智能系统连接起来。
these intelligent systems together.
这些智能系统一起。
So I wanna go through a little bit of some of the building blocks of this.
所以我想稍微讲解一下其中的一些基本构件。
And I know I don't have that much time, and
我知道我没有那么多时间，而且
I could talk about this for probably three hours.
我大概可以谈这个话题三个小时。
So at one point, Ken, I hope that you cut me.
所以在某个时刻，Ken，我希望你打断我。
And I'm looking at Lucia's comments,
我正在看露西亚的评论，
I shouldn't do that, I should just go on with my presentation.
我不应该那样做，我应该继续进行我的演讲。
So the challenge here, I think I mentioned it,
那么这里的挑战，我想我提到过，
is this multisource multi-destination data capture and decision making.
这是多源多目的地数据捕获和决策制定。
I have a bunch of sensors, I have a bunch of cameras, I have a bunch of microphones.
我有一堆传感器，我有一堆摄像头，我有一堆麦克风。
They're all listening, they're all doing something.
它们都在倾听，它们都在做一些事情。
And they may want to go to different destinations and
他们可能想去不同的目的地。
take decisions now or take decision later.
现在做决定还是稍后做决定。
And this is where some of the NDN concepts come in.
这就是一些NDN概念发挥作用的地方。
And obviously it's all heterogeneous, and it's heterogeneous environments and
这显然都是异构的，包括异构环境和
heterogeneous sensors, and obviously heterogeneous datasets.
异构传感器，显然还包括异构数据集。
So what I'm looking at for this is kind of building, and
所以我看到的是某种正在建设中的东西，以及
you're going to see, some kind of the building blocks.
你将会看到，某种正在建设中的基础部分。
So obviously there's this NDN and ICN,
所以很明显，这里有NDN和ICN，
which because it's so data driven needs to
所以因为它非常依赖数据，需要去
address the right type of information.
处理正确类型的信息。
I also talk about well compute first networking is
我还会谈论首先要计算好网络是如何运作的。
from a version of computing and the network in a way.
从一种计算和网络的方式来看。
And this whole architecture takes advantage,
这整个架构利用了优势，
I see, I'll come back to the answers later,
我明白了，我稍后会回来查看答案。
I should stop looking at the thing.
我应该停止看那个东西。
Anyway, so there's also this heritage of COIN, because COIN has
Anyway, so there's also this heritage of COIN, because COIN has 处理了很多本地计算的问题，
addressed a lot of the local computing,
处理了很多本地计算的问题，
especially at the edge, but also in the data center in the cloud.
尤其是在边缘计算领域，同时也包括数据中心和云计算。
So in a way, although this session is called edge, I would say what
所以在某种程度上，尽管这个环节被称为边缘计算，我想说的是什么
I'm presenting is a cloud-supported edge.
我在介绍的是一个云支持的边缘。
So it doesn't really work together, and I'm sorry,
所以它们并不真正协同工作，我很抱歉，
there's a truck on the street here, it's next generation IoT.
这里街上有一辆卡车，它是下一代物联网技术。
I mentioned that it's a mix of edge and cloud computing, it's obviously data
我提到它是边缘计算和云计算的结合，这显然是数据相关的。
driven system, which are more and more what is happening in IoT.
驱动系统，这在物联网中越来越普遍。
Semantic Web because we need to name these things and
语义网，因为我们需要为这些东西命名并且
make sure that they can be discoverable, and it's also distributed networks.
确保它们可以被发现，同时它也是分布式网络。
So I call it the decision making building blocks.
所以我称它为决策制定的基石。
So what are they?
所以它们是什么？
Well, we started, and I hope Eve is still on the call,
嗯，我们已经开始了，我希望Eve还在通话中，
we started looking at some kind of a common data layer.
我们开始研究某种公共数据层。
This with colleagues at Ericsson Research in Finland and
这是与芬兰爱立信研究院的同事们一起进行的工作。
someone who was doing a postdoc at Princeton.
这是在普林斯顿大学做博士后的某人。
And we started thinking that in all these systems,
我们开始认为，在所有这些系统中，
we're talking that there are a number of functionality that are common.
我们在讨论有许多功能是共通的。
And they're not a network layer, they are a data layer.
它们不是一个网络层，它们是一个数据层。
And what do we wanna do with this data layer is discovery and chaining.
我们想要用这个数据层做的是发现和链接。
I wanna know what information is important,
我想知道哪些信息是重要的。
adding obviously levels of security.
增加了显而易见的安全级别。
We wanna do some filtering, this actually comes from some of the work in
我们想要做一些过滤工作，这实际上源自一些工作，在
computing in a network where there's more and more programmable switches.
我们想要做一些过滤工作，这实际上源自一些工作，在一个网络计算环境中，那里有越来越多的可编程交换机。That can go to very high speed but can also be very useful in filtering the type.
That can go to very high speed but can also be very useful in filtering the type
这可以达到非常高的速度，但在过滤我们想要的信息类型方面也可以非常有用。
of information we want, and send it to other processes we need to do it.
它可以筛选我们想要的信息，并将其发送到我们需要进行处理的其他流程中。
It's actually a lot of processing and orchestration,
它实际上涉及大量的处理和协调工作，
especially while I put two elements there that could be much more than that.
尤其是当我在那里放置了两个元素，而实际上可能远不止这些。
So we wanna do this processing and this orchestration,
因此我们想要进行这个处理和这个协调工作，
while at the same time doing the discovery and the chaining and
同时进行发现和链接工作，
being able to create better functionality.
能够创造更好的功能。
But I was saying based on the functionality that you can,
但我是基于你能够创造更好的功能来说的，
in comma, borrow somewhere else.
在逗号中，借用其他地方。
Obviously I put data acquisition there, but it could be anything,
显然我在那里放置了数据采集，但其实它可以是任何东西，
could be actually data producers in general.
它们实际上可以是一般的数据生产者。
And a big thing there is we would like to have local decision making.
我们希望能够实现本地决策。
And this actually comes to the point where that's why we wanna have local processing.
这实际上说明了为什么我们想要进行本地处理的原因。
We wanna have local processing down at the data acquisition.
我们希望在数据采集处进行本地处理。
And we wanna have it at local decision at the edge, and that could mean at the edge
我们希望在边缘处做出本地决策，这可能意味着在边缘位置。
of the industrial facility.
的工业设施边缘。
It could be at the edge of a city, it could be at the edge of a car.
它可能位于城市的边缘，也可能位于汽车的边缘。
But this means that there's distributed intelligence everywhere,
但这意味着到处都有分布式智能，
so this is actually our common data layer.
所以这实际上是我们的共享数据层。
We want also to have an embedded decision layer at the same time.
我们也希望同时拥有一个嵌入式的决策层。
This is that intelligence layer that, again,
这就是那个智能层，再次，
is now being pushed by a number of people to make local decision.
正在被许多人推动做出本地决策。
And it's actually for me or for other people is not local,
而实际上对我或其他人来说，并不是本地的，
it's actually cloud supported.
它其实是云支持的。
Nobody's ever going to train neural networks in a Raspberry Pi.
没有人会在树莓派上训练神经网络。
But a Raspberry Pi can actually do a lot of things that
但是树莓派实际上能做很多事情，这些事情是通过在云端训练你的数据集得来的。
are derived from training your datasets in the cloud.
是通过在云端训练你的数据集得来的。
It's obviously a lot of AI and machine learning.
这显然涉及大量的人工智能和机器学习。
And again, and this goes back to what the previous slide, but also to some of
这又回到了前一张幻灯片的内容，也与一些
the concepts in NDN and in COIN right now, which is the resource and data discovery.
这又回到了前一张幻灯片的内容，也与一些目前在NDN和COIN中的概念相关，即资源和数据发现。
We need to know where the intelligence is,
我们需要知道智能所在的位置。
we need to know what algorithms need to be turned on and off.
我们需要知道哪些算法需要开启和关闭。
And again, there's this ID of interest messages and
再次提到，还有这个兴趣消息的ID和
the response to the interest messages that actually tag the packets.
对兴趣消息的响应实际上标记了数据包。
And I think in our view of it, we want the packets to be tied to
在我们看来，我们希望将数据包与之关联
the level of even, >> That could be implemented
在我们看来，我们希望将数据包与之关联，在这些可编程交换机和数据平面上实现的程度甚至，>> That could be implemented
on these programmable switches and dataplane.
在这些可编程交换机和数据平面上。
So I know that Dave is on online and I think there's been a lot of
所以我知道Dave在线上，我认为有很多
discussions here about what it means to be the difference between
讨论在这里关于存在于...之间的差异意味着什么
in the network, and on the network, and I think this is both.
在网络内部和网络上，我认为这两者都包括了。
So this is an ID of currently something that is being implemented or
所以这是一个当前正在实施中的某种东西的ID，或者
actually a version of it and where the intelligent
实际上是它的一个版本，以及智能
gateway implements both the common data layer.
网关实现了通用数据层。
And the the intelligence layer to make a local decisions and
以及智能层进行本地决策
then sense stuff that is necessary to the web.
然后感知对网络来说必要的信息。
What this thing does is essentially trying to implement as much as possible,
这个东西的本质功能是尽可能地实现，
the decisions that are needed
所需的决策
by the data acquisition systems to make the decisions to filter the information,
通过数据采集系统进行决策以过滤信息，
to essentially profit from some of the lower
为了从一些较低层面上获得实际利益，
layer Pub/sub protocols like MQTT and COAP.
层发布/订阅协议，如MQTT和COAP。
And actually, we'll start putting that intelligence there.
实际上，我们将开始在那里部署智能技术。
Many reasons to do that,
有很多理由这么做，
one is if we wanna start having very autonomous systems,
我们想要开始拥有非常自主的系统，
we cannot always think that they're going to be connected all the time,
我们不能总是认为它们会一直保持连接状态，
especially if we want to go into a remote area.
尤其是如果我们想要进入一个偏远地区。
And where we cannot,
而在我们无法做到的地方，
although the 5G people are gonna say there's gonna be 5G everywhere.
尽管那些支持5G的人会说到处都会有5G网络。
Well, I know Northern Quebec unfortunately color into winter.
嗯，我知道北魁北克不幸地进入了冬天。
I wouldn't bet on that.
我不会对此抱有太大希望。
And so has to be, I think what you can see from this very simple view is that
因此必须如此，我认为从这个非常简单的视角你可以看出
there's different type of data producers in here who have very simple controllers.
这里有不同类型的数据生产者，他们拥有非常简单的控制器。
They do the wrong, the on, off.
他们做错了，只有开和关。
They only can read something.
他们只能读一些东西。
There's a lot of analog systems still and an IoT or
有很多模拟系统仍然存在，以及物联网或者……
IoT related group >> Got under three minutes total.
物联网相关小组 >> 总共不到三分钟。
>> Okay, I'm actually going to go really fast and
好的，我实际上会讲得非常快，
then you have all these different things.
那么你就有了所有这些不同的东西。
So let me go.
那么让我开始吧。
So the use cases, I'm gonna go really fast on this.
所以关于使用案例，我会非常快速地介绍。
I just a few.
我只有几个。
Design and manufacturing, the goals.
设计和制造，这些是目标。
It's IoT digital twins, data driven approaches.
物联网数字孪生，数据驱动方法。
Again, you have the tactile, the dotnet.
再次提到，你有触觉，有dotnet。
This is when the FlexNGIA comes in and those building blocks.
这就是FlexNGIA及其构建模块发挥作用的时候。
So this is what I'm saying is you wanna create these big building blocks.
所以我想说的是，你想要创建这些大型的构建模块。
You may wanna have edge or information centric networking for the distribution,
你可能想要使用边缘或信息中心网络来进行分发，
the quality of service.
服务质量。
You want ARVR functionality, cuz you wanna have the images and
你想要ARVR功能，因为你想要拥有那些图像和
you wanna be able to overlay images, even for
你想要能够叠加图像，即使是为了
some of the other systems and I didn't really mention there was little
一些其他的系统，我没有真正提到那里有一点
security thing all over the architecture and that was actually the blockchains.
安全性问题贯穿于整个架构，而这实际上就是区块链。
And right now, the idea of linking blockchains to AI is pretty cool.
目前，将区块链与人工智能相结合的想法非常酷。
This is what has been keeping me busy for 18 months now
这已经让我忙碌了18个月了。
is these idea of connected vertical agriculture environments.
这些想法是关于相互连接的垂直农业环境。
Essentially you want automated climate proof production,
本质上你想要的是自动化的抗气候影响的生产。
you want them to be intelligence.
你希望它们具备智能。
You wanna be able to dis rump them to be autonomous and discovered their data,
你希望能够使它们具有自主性并发现它们的数据。
their resources.
他们的资源。
Do a lot of edge sensor data cloud support a decision.
边缘传感器的大量数据是否能够支持云端做出决策。
I know the people after B are presenting some ideas in that we're coding.
我知道B之后的人们在提出一些关于我们进行编码的想法。
Well, there's actually some ideas of network coding here to protect
嗯，这里实际上有一些关于网络编码的想法用来保护
the information.
保护信息。
You wanna have the blockchain again and the local intelligence for
您想再次拥有区块链以及本地智能。
amongst other things, detecting diseases, but also I should have added that.
在其他事情中，还包括检测疾病，但我本应该补充那一点的。
So detect what you want to do your harvest.
所以，找出你想要做的事情并收获成果。
Multimedia, this is what got me started and all this thing.
多媒体，这正是让我开始投入并全身心投入的东西。
Again, same building blocks, very different application.
再一次，相同的构建模块，却有着非常不同的应用。
And also the in that case, the blockchain the small contracts are also to
在那种情况下，区块链上的小型合约也会
monetize when you distribute the information and
在你分发信息时实现货币化，
we heard about the self-driving vehicles, self-drivers for insurance.
我们听说了关于自动驾驶车辆，自动驾驶车辆的保险。
The cars that platforms.
这些是平台的汽车。
Cars the platform is again is from my friend works for Ford and
这些是平台的汽车，再次来自于我的朋友，他在福特工作。
he's not the guy presented yesterday.
他不是昨天介绍的那个人。
Building blocks again, same thing.
积木又来了，还是同样的东西。
So you see, what I think we want.
所以你看，我认为我们想要的是什么。
I'm still looking at the questions.
我还在看问题。
I shouldn't be doing this and- >> I need to wrap it up, please.
我不应该这么做，我需要结束了，请。
>> Okay, so I'm done.
好的，那我结束了。
Okay. >> Conclusion.
好的。>> 结束。
>> [LAUGH] >> That's it, we're done.
>> [笑声] >> 就这样，我们完成了。
>> Okay, so I think we're gonna go on to the next thing.
>> 好的，我认为我们将继续进行下一件事。
>> No, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, give me 30 seconds.
>> 不，等等，等一下，等一下，等一下，给我30秒。
>> Okay. >> This is actually all the people
>> 好的。>> 这实际上是所有人
who control contributed and I really, really want people to look at this.
谁控制了贡献，我真的非常希望人们能关注这个。
>> Okay, great, thanks a lot out.
>> 好的，太棒了，非常感谢。
We're gonna defer questions to the chat and I advise the next speaker not to look
我们将把问题留到聊天环节，我建议下一位发言者不要看聊天内容，因为那里可能正在进行讨论。
at the chat, because there might be a discussion going on there
我们将在聊天环节讨论，因为那里可能正在进行讨论。
which is about the previous talk which is what happened this time.
这是关于之前的讲话，也就是这次发生的事情。
But our next speaker is Hirah Malik.
但我们的下一位演讲者是Hirah Malik。
She's a researcher at Inria in France.
她是法国国家信息与自动化研究所(Inria)的一名研究员。
She's working on her PhD at University of Paris-Saclay in France and
她正在法国巴黎-萨克雷大学攻读博士学位，并且
she did her master's in multimedia networking from Telecom, Paris Tech.
她在巴黎高科电信学院获得了多媒体网络硕士学位。
And her research interests are multimedia delivery and data set synchronization
她的研究兴趣包括多媒体传输和数据集同步。
in ICN, and NDN, and she's now working on network coding in Indiana.
她现在在印第安纳州研究网络编码，并且她的研究涉及到ICN和NDN。
And her talk is on MICN which is a new perspective on network coding.
她的演讲是关于MICN的，这是对网络编码的一种新视角。
So take it away here.
那么请开始吧。
Thank you.
谢谢。
>> Thank you for the kind introduction.
>> 谢谢你的友好介绍。
Hello, everyone.
大家好。
I'm Hirah Malik.
我是Hirah Malik。
First of all, I would like to thank the organizers for
首先，我想感谢组织者给予我
this opportunity to present in NDN com.
这次机会在NDN com上发表演讲。
I will be presenting today an ICN,
今天我将在NDN com上发表演讲，介绍一种ICN，
which is a protocol that combines network coding with named data networking.
它是一种将网络编码与命名数据网络结合的协议。
We'll begin with a little background and
我们将从一些背景知识开始讲起。
explain a little bit the motivation for combining the two.
解释一下将这两者结合起来的动机。
So in a scenario where a client wants to retrieve a large content
所以在一个客户端想要检索大量内容的场景中
with no knowledge of the network, no topology known.
在不了解网络、不知道网络拓扑的情况下。
The natural solution is to exploit multiple paths and
利用多条路径是一个自然的解决方案。
NDN allows us to do that, but
NDN允许我们这样做，但是
in a classical Indian scenario as shown in this example.
在这个例子中展示的典型印度情境中。
If a client has to recover, let's say content with two segments, P1 and P2.
如果一个客户需要恢复内容，比如有两个部分，P1和P2。
It will naturally start requesting the content P1.
它将自然开始请求内容P1。
And if it sends interest on the two available paths that we see here,
如果它在我们这里看到的两条可用路径上发送兴趣，
it will end up getting twice the same content from the two links
它最终会从这两个链接中获取两次相同的内容。
which is just redundant content.
这只是重复的内容。
A solution to this is network coding.
解决这个问题的一个方法是网络编码。
I will go ahead and present a little bit network coding first.
我将首先简要介绍一下网络编码。
So network coding allows combining packets in the network.
所以网络编码允许在网络中组合数据包。
They can be combined in several ways.
它们可以通过几种方式组合起来。
They can be absorbed.
它们可以被吸收。
They can be added or the nodes could do linear combinations of the source packet.
它们可以被添加，或者节点可以对源数据包进行线性组合。
The coding and recording can be done anywhere in the network, and
编码和记录可以在网络的任何地方完成，
decoding is easy.
解码很简单。
It's basically solving a linear system of equations once a client
解码很简单。一旦客户端收到足够的编码数据包，它就可以执行逆向
has received enough coded packets that it can perform inverse
已经收到足够的编码数据包，它就可以执行逆向操作
operations to recover the source packets.
操作以恢复源数据包。
So to illustrate how NDN benefits from network coding,
因此，为了说明NDN如何从网络编码中受益，
we can see that in the same scenario.
我们可以看到，在同样的情景下。
Now if the clients request for the coded packets of the same content which has
我们可以看到，在同样的情景下，如果客户端请求相同内容的编码数据包，two sort of segments And sends over these two over the multiple variable paths.
two sort of segments And sends over these two over the multiple variable paths.
两种类型的数据段，并通过多个可变路径发送这两个数据段。
Source one sends a coded packet, which is a mix of two p1 and P2,
源一发送了一个编码数据包，它是两个数据包p1和p2的混合。
and source two sends a different mix of the source packets.
源二发送了一个不同的源数据包混合。
The client can retrieve the source packets by
客户端可以通过解码这些线性独立的编码数据包来检索源数据包。
decoding these linearly independent coded packets.
解码这些线性独立的编码数据包。
The idea to use network coding has been around for a while, which
网络编码的概念已经存在一段时间了，它
gave us the motivation to do a protocol which we call MICN.
给了我们动力去开发一种我们称之为MICN的协议。
Which ensures high throughput by avoiding redundant content.
它通过避免冗余内容来确保高吞吐量。
So we start with the classical way of implementing network coding over NDN,
所以我们从在NDN上实现网络编码的经典方式开始，
which others do as well.
其他人也是这样做的。
So we have the same information bases.
所以我们有相同的信息基础。
We have the content store, the PIT and the FIB, and the same messages.
我们有内容存储、PIT和FIB，以及相同的消息。
But everything now accounts for the fact that we are requesting, processing, and
但现在的一切都说明了我们正在请求、处理和
forwarding coded content.
转发编码内容。
And however to make it work, there have to be major semantic changes in NDN.
为了使其工作，必须在NDN中进行重大的语义更改。
And to test everything here, we implemented it in a simulator in Python.
为了在这里测试一切，我们在Python模拟器中实现了它。
So to explain the NDN semantics, as I've said already,
为了解释NDN语义，正如我已经说过的，
the central goal is for us is to have high throughput with multiple paths and
我们的核心目标是通过多条路径实现高吞吐量，
we focus on this goal hundred percent.
我们百分之百地专注于这个目标。
And with this assumption that there is no coordination among the nodes.
在这个假设下，节点之间没有协调。
So focusing on our goal, the first thing is to improve or
因此，聚焦于我们的目标，首先要做的是提升或者
increase the interest propagation in the network.
增加网络中的兴趣传播。
And the first design choice for that is easy,
而做出这个选择的第一步很简单，
you choose a forwarding strategy that allows you to do that.
你选择了一个允许你这样做的转发策略。
So we choose a multicast forwarding strategy,
所以我们选择了一种多播转发策略，
which sends interest over all the available paths.
它通过所有可用的路径发送兴趣。
Another design choice that we make to complement multicast,
我们做出的另一个设计选择是为了补充多播，
to improve the interest propagation, is we modified interest processing,
我们做出的另一个设计选择是修改了兴趣处理方式，以改善兴趣传播，
which is also not that difficult, but is important and vital for our problem.
这也并不是很难，但对我们的问题来说是重要且至关重要的。
And the third and the most important is that we enable processing of multiple
并且第三个也是最重要的是，我们实现了多个处理过程。
parallel interests in NDN, which I will be explaining in detail later.
在NDN中的并行兴趣点，我稍后会详细解释。
So, the first one is the NIC, the interest processing,
所以，第一个是NIC，兴趣处理，
the modified interest processing.
修改后的兴趣处理。
So in classical NDN, it limits the diffusion of interest.
因此，在传统的NDN中，它限制了兴趣的扩散。
So as we can see here in this example, if the client one sends interest,
因此，正如我们在这个例子中看到的，如果客户端一发送兴趣，
since we're using a multicast strategy, so it's multicasted over all the available
因为我们使用的是多播策略，所以它会在所有可用的~!@#$%^&*()
paths to reach the source one and two, and it creates this multicast tree.
它会在源头一和源头二的所有可用路径上创建这个多播树。
Now when the client two enters later and sends its interest for the content,
当客户端二稍后进入并发送其对内容的兴趣时，
they will be suppressed because of clients one's interest.
它们会因为客户端一的兴趣而被抑制。
And they could only reach to this router close to client one, but
它们只能到达靠近客户端一的这台路由器，但是
they will not reach the source one and two, and client two cannot
它们将无法到达源头一和源头二，客户端二也不能
effectively use all of the available paths that it has to the sources.
有效地使用它通往源头的所有可用路径。
So, a solution to this is not doing interest suppression for similar interest,
因此，解决这个问题的方法是不压制相似的兴趣。
and this is what we do, MICN do not suppress a similar interest.
我们就是这么做的，MICN不会压制相似的兴趣。
So which effectively increases the number of interests in the network but
所以这实际上增加了网络中的兴趣数量，但是
also increase the propagation and lets the interest reach the sources.
因此这实际上增加了传播，让兴趣触及源头。
The other important point is that I've said before is to have multiple parallel
另一个重要的点是，我之前说过的，就是拥有多个并行的
interests, to enable multiple parallel interests that we call pipelining.
兴趣流，以实现我们所说的多个并行兴趣，即管道化。
By the name of it, it might seem trivial because NDN allows sending
根据它的名字，这似乎微不足道，因为NDN允许发送
multiple parallel interests to be sent in the network, but
但这允许在网络中发送多个并行的兴趣。
[INAUDIBLE] that if a client [INAUDIBLE] interest for
~!@#$%^&*()
a coded segment or for a set of source segments and
一个编码段或一组源段和
it receives this coded segment from a source.
它从一个源接收到这个编码段。
And when it sends another interest for the same set of coded segment,
当它再次发送对同一编码段集的兴趣请求时，
the same coded content can be a response to this interest and to all the next ones.
相同的编码内容可以作为对这一兴趣请求以及所有后续兴趣请求的响应。
Because it's requesting coded segments of the same set of source packets.
因为它请求的是同一组源数据包的编码片段。
This is specific case but it can happen actually anywhere in the network.
这是一个特殊案例，但实际上它可能发生在网络的任何地方。
And here, the figure on the right we can see that the same content can flow back
在这里，我们可以看到右边的图示，同样的内容可以流回来，
from different sources, different routers in the network,
来自不同的来源，网络中的不同路由器，
given that they have received this content from a similar source.
鉴于他们从一个类似的来源接收到了这个内容。
And this is a major problem.
这是一个主要问题。
This is one important problem that we need to solve because for a client to decode
这是我们需要解决的一个重要问题，因为要让客户解码，
a content it should have enough linearly independent content to decode.
这是我们需要解决的一个重要问题，因为要让客户解码，内容必须包含足够的线性独立信息。为了解决这个问题，我们提出了一个我们称之为MILIC的解决方案，这是为了
To solve this problem, we propose the solution we call MILIC, which is for
为了解决这个问题，我们提出了一个我们称之为MILIC的解决方案，这是为了
end source segments, we send n indexed interests,
为了结束源段落，我们发送了n个索引兴趣，
and so, these interests bring content from predefined subsets.
因此，这些兴趣能够从预定义的子集中带回内容。
That is the an interest I1 will bring back content
因此，兴趣 I1 将带回内容
from the subset A1 and similarly for I2, it brings back from A2 and
从子集 A1 中，I1 将带回内容，同样地，I2 从 A2 中带回内容，
I3 from A3 such that they're always linearly independent.
I3 从 A3 中带回内容，以确保它们始终是线性独立的。
So, defining such subsets
因此，定义这样的子集
that they are always linearly independent is a mathematical problem.
它们总是线性独立的是一个数学问题。
And we solve this mathematical problem, and
我们解决了这个数学问题，
our solution to this is that we define our subsets like this.
我们解决这个问题的方法是这样定义我们的子集。
I'm going to explain it with this example.
我将用这个例子来解释它。
That interest I1 one can only be responded to for
该兴趣I1只能得到响应以用于
content with three source packets and interest I1 can only
该兴趣I1只能得到响应以用于包含三个源数据包的内容，
be responded with a coded segment that should have the first segment and
可以响应一个编码段，该编码段应该包含第一个段落和
may have the second and third segments.
可以包含第二和第三个编码段。
And same for I2, it should not have the first one,
同样对于I2，它不应该包含第一个编码段。
definitely should have the second segment, and can may have the third segment.
它肯定应该包含第二个编码段，并且可能包含第三个编码段。
And by just looking at this three segment example, we can see that if,
通过观察这个三段示例，我们可以看到如果，
if a node receives responses to I1, I2, and I3, they're all linearly independent.
如果一个节点接收到I1、I2和I3的响应，它们都是线性独立的。
So this is one important property of MILIC construction.
因此，这是MILIC构造的一个重要特性。
There are two other properties since,
这是因为还有两个其他的特性，
as I've already said that we use multiple paths and we are sending in trust
正如我已经说过的，我们使用多条路径，并且我们是在信任中发送。
over multiple paths, we can hope to get several replies to an index.
通过多条路径，我们希望能收到对一个索引的多个回复。
In case we receive several replies, these two other properties ensure that
在我们收到多个回复的情况下，这两个其他属性确保了
the content that comes back in response to to these interest is still useful.
收到这些兴趣响应的内容仍然是有用的。
And if a node receives more than one replies to one interest,
如果一个节点对一个兴趣收到不止一个回复，
it can use it to create content for other subsets, so if another
它可以利用它为其他子集创建内容，因此如果其他
interest arises later they can respond to it.
它可以根据后来产生的兴趣做出响应。
In order to make the protocol work better, we had to do some
为了使协议更好地工作，我们不得不做了一些
additional protocol enhancements, which I'm going to go briefly over.
为了增强协议的功能，我将简要介绍一下。
One of which is just-in-time re-encoding.
其中之一便是即时重新编码。
This is actually a queue management technique
这实际上是一种队列管理技术。
to manage the queues in order to have more diverse content in the network.
为了在网络中拥有更多样化的内容来管理队列。
The second one is interest cancellation, as I said that
第二个是取消兴趣，正如我所说的那样
in my design choices that we effectively send a lot of interest in the network.
在我的设计选择中，我们有效地在网络中引起了很多兴趣。
In order to counter this problem, we introduced this mechanism
为了应对这个问题，我们引入了这个机制。
of interest cancellation that cancels the unnecessary
为了解决这个问题，我们引入了兴趣消除机制，用于取消不必要的兴趣，在客户端接收到内容后，可以减少网络中的兴趣。
interests in the network after the clients have received the content.
在客户端接收到内容之后，可以减少网络中的兴趣。
And the third one is called content redirection which allows
内容重定向，它允许
The less utilized paths to be used when and if it's possible.
不太常用的路径在可能的情况下才使用。
So this is just presented the protocol.
这只是协议的介绍。
Now I'm going to present the protocol performance with some simulation results.
现在我将通过一些模拟结果来展示协议的性能。
So here, we have a network with one source and
所以在这里，我们有一个网络，其中有一个源头和
five clients that you can see in gray that are requesting the same content.
五个客户端以灰色显示，它们正在请求相同的内容。
The content has hundred source segments.
内容包含一百个源段落。
And on the right we can see that there is this.
在右边我们可以看到这个。
This graph presents on y axis the number of linearly independent packets.
这张图表在y轴上展示了线性独立数据包的数量。
That the users received at any time, which is the x axis.
该图表的x轴代表了用户在任何时间点接收的数据。
We can see that all the curves are linear.
我们可以看到所有的曲线都是线性的。
But when we see in detail, we see in fact that all the users
但是当我们仔细观察时，我们实际上可以看到所有用户
are receiving content at their maximum possible throughput.
都在以其最大可能的吞吐量接收内容。
Which is, which was basically the main design goal of MICN and
它基本上是MICN主要设计目标，
in the first place, another important aspect that I've
首先，另一个我已经解释过的重要方面是具有高吞吐量，
explained already is that with high throughput,
已经解释过的是，具有高吞吐量，
we risk overloading the network with a lot of interest, and
我们冒着用大量的兴趣来过载网络的风险，
content and to cater this we introduce Interest cancellation,
内容，并为此我们引入了兴趣取消机制，
and we can see here that we have pretty much solved this
我们可以看到，我们已经基本上解决了这个问题。
problem with this additional enhancement in the protocol.
这个协议中的额外增强功能存在问题。
To conclude MICN is a network coding protocol that mind that recording and
总而言之，MICN是一个网络编码协议，它考虑到了记录和
NDN basically it relies on the milic construction,
总的来说，NDN基本上依赖于milic结构，
that ensures that there is no redundant content flowing in the network,
这确保了网络中没有冗余内容流动。
in response to the to the interest that we send.
响应我们所发出的兴趣。
And I presented the critical improvements that we had to do to make it work better.
我提出了我们必须进行的关键改进，以使其运行得更好。
In future we hope to have improved the interest forwarding strategies.
未来我们希望能改进利益转发策略。
So we can maybe not have the problem of having too
所以我们或许不会再有太多的问题。
many interests in the network after all,
毕竟网络上有很多人感兴趣，
while still reaching high throughput.
虽然如此，仍能保持高吞吐量。
Thank you. That's about it.
谢谢。就是这样。
>> Okay, thanks great hero.
好的，谢谢，伟大的英雄。
Do we have questions?
我们有问题吗？
I have a question.
我有个问题。
So you said you had to make some changes to the Indian protocol,
所以你说你必须对印度协议进行一些更改，
to which extent to those need to be, what sort of your deployment approach or
那些需要在多大程度上进行修改，你的部署策略或方法是什么样的？
strategy can it be confined to the publisher, and
策略是否可以仅限于发布者，以及
the recipient of the data or to do all the network elements have to know that?
数据的接收者或者所有网络元素都必须知道这一点吗？
Could you do this?
你能做到这一点吗？
Could you cram it all into the namespace construction or what?
你能把它们全部塞进命名空间构造中吗？
>> Yeah.
是的。
So as I've said, the changes have to be known across the network.
所以正如我所说，这些更改必须在整个网络中被知晓。
A few of the modifications which is this index that we put in the interest,
这些修改中的一部分是我们放在利益中的索引，
is this information is carried in the interest, but
这些信息是被包含在利益之中的，但
it is protocol specification, and every node is expected to know, these changes.
它是协议规范，每个节点都应该知道这些变化。
These are called changes.
这些被称为变化。
>> Okay.
好的。
I think that subsumes the answer to a question in the chat,
我认为这包含了聊天中一个问题的答案，
which was how do you name the interest differently so
我认为这包含了聊天中一个问题的答案，即如何以不同的方式命名利益？
that a producer responds back with the coded data?
生产者是否会用编码后的数据进行回应？
[CROSSTALK] Yeah, would that send her the interest have to know to ask for
[交叉谈话] 是的，那会不会让她产生兴趣，让她知道该提出请求？
those special name?
那些特别的名字？
>> Yeah, so the interest carries in its name that
是的，所以兴趣在它的名字中承载着
we are requesting for coded content, and
我们正在请求编码内容，和
this MILIC index indicates which coded packet we want in response.
这个MILIC指数指示我们希望响应中包含哪个编码数据包。
>> But that could be I mean, that could be transparent to the to the stack, and
>> 但这可能对于协议栈来说是透明的，我是说，这可能对协议栈是透明的，而且
the clients if it's just in the name or does there have to be?
这是否仅仅在名称上，还是必须要有实质内容？
I obviously in the coding they have to know in the decoding, but
在编码时他们显然必须知道，而在解码时也同样需要知道，但是……
could that be sort of on top of the Indian layer?
这可能位于印度层的上方吗？
>> Yes, actually, >> Part of the transport I mean.
>> 是的，确实，>> 我指的是部分运输工具。
>> Yeah, >> Okay.
>> 是的，>> 好的。
Does MILIC rely on some synchronization between the producers to ensure they all
MILIC是否依赖于生产者之间的某种同步，以确保他们都会
know the same linearly independent subsets.
知道相同的线性无关子集。
>> So, basically this merely construction actually
>> 所以，基本上这仅仅是一个构造实际上
is basically just a subset of encoding vectors.
所以，基本上这仅仅是一个编码向量的子集。
You see, >> Okay.
你看，>> 好的。
>> With just looking at the index, we can see that,
>> 仅仅通过查看索引，我们就可以看出，
okay, these are the constraints that we have to put on the code or content.
好的，这些是我们必须对代码或内容施加的限制。
The first segment needs to be non-zero, and the rest can be chosen randomly.
第一个部分需要是非零的，其他的可以随机选择。
For the second one, first one has to be zero and the second one,
对于第二个，第一个必须是零，第二个，
definitely non-zero, and the rest of it can be chosen randomly.
肯定不是零，其他的可以随机选择。
It's just how we are mixing packets, it's just a constraint on how you mix
我们只是在混合数据包，这只是对你如何混合的一个限制。
packets not that you're splitting content into different sets.
我们并不是在将内容拆分到不同的组中。
>> Okay, thank you very much.
>> 好的，非常感谢。
We're out of time.
我们没有时间了。
I think there's another question in the chat, if you want to look at that later.
我认为聊天中还有一个问题，如果你想的话，稍后可以看看。
But we'll go on to the next speaker, who is at Zhao.
但我们将继续下一位发言人，他是赵先生。
He's a PhD student in the computer science department at UCLA.
他是加州大学洛杉矶分校计算机科学系的博士研究生。
And he's working also as a research scientist,
并且他还担任研究科学家，
at intelligent fusion technology.
在智能融合技术领域。
And he's going to talk about some joint work with some colleagues
他将会讨论一些与同事们的合作研究工作。
from the University of Alabama and City College in New York,
来自阿拉巴马大学和纽约市立学院，
about underwater wireless communication.
关于水下无线通信。
So shall take it away.
那么就开始吧。
>> Okay, thanks.
好的，谢谢。
>> Thank you for coming to this presentation today.
>> 感谢您今天来参加这次演讲。
And I'm gonna present our joint work named
我将要展示我们的合作研究，名为
Data Networking Architecture Design to Internet of Underwater Things.
数据网络架构设计到水下物联网。
So this is the outline for today's presentation.
这是今天演讲的大纲。
And first The question is what is the underwater communication?
首先问题是什么是水下通信？
Or recall the IOUT communication.
或者回想一下IOUT通信。
So a typical internet of underwater things, and
那么一个典型的水下物联网可能会是~!@#$%^&*()
be a three layered network system that involves, first of all,
是一个涉及三层网络系统的，首先是，
a large number of onboard sensors, or acoustic positioning systems,
大量的机载传感器，或声学定位系统，
autonomous underwater vehicles, or unmanned surface vehicle.
自主水下航行器，或无人水面航行器。
And the second part is going to be the acoustic indications, or
第二部分将是声学指示，或者说
local RF links cellular or satellite links, even connecting these things.
本地射频链接、蜂窝或卫星链接，甚至连接这些东西。
The third part is going to be the network topology being like simple single hop or
第三部分将是网络拓扑，如简单的单跳或
ad hoc multiple hops, static or mobile or even cloud based.
多跳自组网，无论是静态的、移动的还是基于云的。
And the last part is actually the user.
最后的部分实际上是用户。
It can be nearby sensors or ABS or like the surface ships or even on the shore.
它可以是附近的传感器、防抱死制动系统（ABS）或者是水面船只，甚至是岸上的设备。
So, the main task of the IOUT is going to be collecting the data, sharing the data,
因此，IOUT的主要任务将是收集数据、共享数据，
and including controlling, and also with possible data analytics in between.
以及包括控制管理，还可能涉及数据分析。
So, to say sometime I will just simply skip this slide for the introduction,
有时候，我会直接跳过这张幻灯片，不做介绍。
but some of the new things that brought by the NDN have to be addressed here
但是必须在这里提到NDN带来的一些新事物。
in this slides, which is actually the interest of data exchange,
在这些幻灯片中，实际上是数据交换的兴趣所在，
the naming the end to end security, the synchronization, and
在这些幻灯片中，实际上是数据交换的兴趣所在，包括了所谓的端到端安全性、数据同步，还有也是实际上依赖于IOUT设计的代码仓库。
also the repo, which is actually IOUT designs, heavily depending on.
此外，代码仓库实际上也是基于IOUT设计的，极大地依赖于它。
So, IOUT is actually similar to the IOT environment,
因此，IOUT实际上与IOT环境类似，
as there are a lot of existing works on Indiana IOT,
因为有很多关于印第安纳州物联网的现有研究，
And they're also showing good benefits, so that's why we are interested
它们也展现出了良好的效益，这就是为什么我们感兴趣的原因。
in implementing again in the IoUT environment.
在IoUT环境中再次实施。
So IoUT has its own challenges, which makes it not exactly like IoUT.
因此，IoUT有其自身的挑战，这使得它并不完全像IoUT。
First of all, it has very complex communication solution,
首先，它有非常复杂的通信解决方案，
the current underwater communication system mainly rely on acoustic
当前的水下通信系统主要依赖于声学
communication technologies.
通信技术。
The large propagation delay and also the high bit error rate of the underwater
大的传播延迟以及水下高比特误差率
acoustic channels still hurt the communication performance review.
声学信道仍然影响通信性能的评估。
Also, we got some new communication technology
此外，我们还获得了一些新的通信技术。
in the recent year like the optical or magneto communications.
在近年来，比如光学或磁通通信。
Even though they improve the performance in terms of the throughput,
尽管它们在吞吐量方面提高了性能，
delay or reliability, but the hardware frontends employing this underwater
延迟或可靠性，但是采用这种水下的硬件前端设备，
communication technologies may have various radios like network interfaces.
通信技术可能有各种各样的无线电设备，如网络接口。
And also, the links potentially was different at addressing system,
而且，链接在寻址系统上也可能有所不同，
the IP subnet and mapping mechanisms between network layer packets and
IP子网和网络层数据包与~!@#$%^&*()之间的映射机制
application data.
应用数据。
So on the other hand, identification and
因此，另一方面，识别和
tracking technology are quite different from the traditional wireless networks or
跟踪技术与传统无线网络相比有很大的不同，或者
wide IoUT, which leaves complicated addressing other things.
宽广的IoUT，这导致了复杂的寻址等问题。
And the last thing is access to all connected devices in IoUT requires either
访问IoUT中所有连接设备的最后一项要求是需要通过局部中间件或管理相关的设备。
a local middleware or to manage associated or
访问IoUT中所有连接设备的最后一项要求是需要通过局部中间件或管理相关的设备，或通过远程云服务来处理数据检索和分发。
remote cloud service to handle the data retrieval and distribution.
远程云服务来处理数据检索和分发。
So developing such an overlay on top of the host-to-host communication model is
在主机到主机通信模型之上开发这样一个覆盖层是
non-trivial, and let alone the maintaining it
非常不简单，更不用说维护它了。
in the dynamic scenario where all devices in network interfaces and
在动态场景中，网络接口中的所有设备和~!@#$%^&*()
communication channels may change constantly.
通信渠道可能会不断变化。
And we still got a lot, some other challenges, for
我们还面临着许多其他挑战，例如
example, the energy, IoUT devices have
例如，IoUT设备的能源问题，
very limited operation lifetime due to the space limit for batteries.
由于电池空间限制，操作寿命非常有限。
And also comparing the power we can see acoustic communications are power hungry.
而且从能耗方面来看，声波通信非常耗电。
And also, unlike IoUT, replacing those batteries or
而且，与IoUT不同，更换这些电池或者
energy recharging can be a very very hard things.
能量充电可能是一件非常非常困难的事情。
Next thing is the bandwidth and mobility, so
下一件事是带宽和移动性，所以
IoUT will bring underwater related research fields into a Big Data era.
IoUT将把水下相关研究领域带入大数据时代。
And the ability of generating and collecting data from IoUT devices can
IoUT设备生成和收集数据的能力可以
easily suppress the communication capability when transferring them.
在传输过程中容易抑制通信能力。
And some other things like reliability,
还有一些其他方面，比如可靠性，
that means the acoustic communication suffers from very high bit error rate.
这意味着声学通信遭受着非常高的比特错误率。
And also the data is required to be received in sequence without
并且数据还需要按顺序接收，不得
loss even though TCP can handle this, but it's inefficient.
丢失即使TCP能够处理这个问题，但它效率不高。
And also, one last thing is the security,
而且，最后一点是安全性，
in IoUT, the data is private to some applications.
在物联网中，数据对某些应用程序是私有的。
And devices are normally costly, and also, the current solution does not fit for
而设备通常成本高昂，同时，现有解决方案并不适用于
IoUT.
Internet of Underwater Things.
So, why we think NFN fits for IoUT, first of all, NDN,
所以，我们为什么认为NFN适合IoUT，首先，NDN，
And entities by replacing them with the unified data named based API's.
并通过统一的基于数据命名的API来替换这些实体。
So this leads to a significant shift of the requirement for the domain use.
因此，这导致了对领域使用需求的重大转变。
And the second thing is the NDN architecture bring efficiency via
因此，第二点是NDN架构通过以下方式带来了效率：
in-network caching and
在网络缓存和
balancing multiple factors of bandwidth latency, energy and also mobility.
在网络缓存和平衡带宽、延迟、能源以及移动性等多个因素方面，And also, NDN enables security binding to data self, unifying and
And also, NDN enables security binding to data self, unifying and
同时，NDN实现了数据自身的安全绑定，统一并且
easing the management of the access and trust of the data and network operations.
简化了数据和网络操作的访问和信任管理。
So here is the figure showing the overview of our proposed NDN architecture to IoUT.
这里是我们提出的面向IoUT的NDN架构概览的图示。
So to deal with various underlying communication technologies that
因此为了处理各种底层通信技术，它们与TCP/IP协议栈兼容，
are compatible with the TCP IP protocol stack,
因此，为了处理各种底层通信技术，它们与TCP/IP协议栈兼容，
a practical way is to create an NDN overlay as the middleware.
因此，一个实用的方法是创建一个NDN（命名数据网络）覆盖网络作为中间件。
That overlay will handle the functionalities of mapping network
该覆盖网络将负责处理网络映射的功能。
interfaces to underwater devices, managing the namespace of the intended data and
接口连接到水下设备，管理预定数据的命名空间和
managing the security of the communication.
管理通信的安全性。
Additional efforts are needed as well here, for example,
需要在这里也做出额外的努力，例如，
a layer two configuration to ensure traffic flows among heterogeneous
需要在这里也做出额外的努力，例如，二层配置以确保不同类型的流量能够相互流通，IoUT子网、IP地址和端口号的分配管理。
IoUT subnets, IP address, and port number assignment management for
IoUT子网、IP地址和端口号的分配管理用于
network connectivity or even the secure data collecting and also forwarding.
网络连接，甚至是安全数据的收集和转发。
So let's take a quick look at the some of the parts that we propose to implement.
那么，让我们快速看一下我们提议实施的一些部分。
First of all, it is the data and naming, so NDN uses meaningful names for
首先是数据和命名，因此NDN使用有意义的名称来表示
application data instead of in-host address at the network layer.
应用数据而不是在网络层的主机地址。
So, example showing here, a hierarchical human readable name is used for
所以，这里展示的例子中，使用了分层的、人类可读的名称来
water temperature data responding to a surface node.
水温数据响应一个表层节点。
With NDN, users can use interest data to express the control commands as well.
在NDN中，用户也可以使用兴趣数据来表达控制命令。
The mechanism is to carry the control commands as the parameter field
该机制是将控制命令作为参数字段携带。
in the interest data, in the interest packet, and
在兴趣数据中，在兴趣包中，
send the interest to device without prior interest on the command.
将兴趣发送到设备，而无需预先对命令表示兴趣。
So, such interest can contain a target name, the target node name prefix and
所以，这样的兴趣可以包含一个目标名称、目标节点名称前缀以及
the corresponding commands need to be delivered to the target nodes, for
相应的命令需要传送给目标节点，为了
example, like the surface, move left, and 50 metres
例如，向左移动表面，移动50米。
[COUGH] So this one is showing the basic name-based routing and forwarding.
（咳嗽声）所以这个展示的是基于名称的基本路由和转发。
One thing that I wanna add here is that the existing underwater routing
我想在这里补充一点，现有的水下路由
protocol actually can be revised and used for
协议实际上可以被修订并使用于
data publisher to advertise the name prefix in NDN architecture.
数据发布者在NDN架构中宣传名称前缀。
For example, some sensing data can be published by the sensor at the sea for
例如，一些传感数据可以由海上的传感器发布。
while the user can be also at the surface.
而用户也可以在水面上。
And the depths based on what routing protocol can be used by this sensors for
而这些传感器可以根据哪种路由协议在深水中使用，以便在水面上更好地传输数据和传递信息。
better data forward and passes.
更好地数据转发和传递。
Similarly, air location information is part of the names and
同样，空中位置信息是名称的一部分并且
geo-routing based on water routing protocols
基于水路路由协议的地理路由
can be employed to help populating the prefix for the data as well.
可以用来帮助填充数据的前缀。
Next part is the in-network storage, the IoUT applications can
下一部分是网络内存储，IoUT应用可以同时利用所有类型的网络内存储。
leverage all types of in-network storage at the same time.
同时利用所有类型的网络内存储。
For example, the underwater sensors can transfer,
例如，水下传感器可以传输，
cut the data immediately to nearby deploy the repository,
立即切断数据，将仓库部署在附近。
since it's costly to encrypt large storage on those sensors.
由于在这些传感器上加密大容量存储成本很高。
And then, the surface users can retrieve the data from the repository instead of
然后，地面用户可以从存储库中检索数据，而不是直接从传感器中获取。
sensors whenever the available bandwidth is sufficient.
传感器会在可用带宽充足时进行数据传输。
And when collected data is requested by multiple users,
当多个用户请求收集的数据时，
in-network opportunistic caches can also help with efficient data forwarding
网络中的机会性缓存也可以帮助高效地转发数据。
by reducing the transmission hops and the propagation distance.
通过减少传输跳数和传播距离。
So due to the sparsity and mobility characteristic of IoUT,
因此，由于IoUT的稀疏性和移动性特征，
the network connectivity may not always been ratained.
因此，网络连接可能并不总是保持连续的。
And the communication must be delay tolerant where endings in network storage
因此，通信必须能够容忍延迟，在网络存储中结束。
can perfectly fit in.
可以完美地适应。
So next two slides, we will take a look at some of the functionality that needed and
接下来的两张幻灯片中，我们将会看一些需要的功能。
also provided by NDN.
同时也由NDN提供。
We actually borrowed some of the idea from the NDN IoUT work.
我们实际上借鉴了NDN IoUT工作中的一些想法。
So here, the first one is about the bootstrapping and the service discovery.
所以这里，第一个是关于启动和服务发现。
So in traditional IP now device, bootstrapping and
So in traditional IP network devices, bootstrapping and
service discovery usually involve complicated and tedious operations, which
通常涉及复杂和繁琐的操作。
is even worse when dealing with different networks and communication medias.
在处理不同的网络和通信媒介时，情况甚至更糟。
So, here in NDN, bootstrapping and
因此，在NDN中，引导和~!@#$%^&*()
service discovery can be simplified by just the use In the interest data
服务发现可以通过简化地使用兴趣数据来实现。
requested responded permitted to deliver three key configurations for the devices.
请求的响应允许为设备提供三个关键配置。
The first one is a proper name prefix for naming the produced data.
第一个是为生成的数据命名的适当前缀。
The second one is a proper assigning and encryption keys for
第二个是适当分配和加密密钥以用于
encrypting the produced data.
加密所生成的数据。
And the last one is a trust anchor and the decryption keys for
以及最后一个是信任锚和用于解密的密钥
consuming the retrieve the data.
消耗资源以检索数据。
So this figure is actually shows a very simple example
所以这个图实际上展示了一个非常简单的例子
of how the bootstrapping works.
所以这个图实际上展示了一个非常简单的例子，它说明了引导程序是如何工作的。And also the next slides is showing the service discovery.
And also the next slides is showing the service discovery.
接下来的幻灯片将展示服务发现。
So here basically is we're gonna learn the existing service from the controller.
所以基本上我们要从控制器那里学习现有的服务。
And then we're gonna advertise the service by
接着我们将通过广播方式宣传这项服务，
broadcasting advertisement after the bootstrapping.
启动之后进行广播广告。
And then the broadcasting again, will happen like when the service changes and
然后当服务发生变化时，再次进行广播。
restarts.
重新启动。
One last thing that we want to say is about Adaptation Layers.
我们想说的最后一件事是关于适应层。
Adaptation is important to give IoT users
适应性对于给物联网用户带来全面的NDN好处是非常重要的，而且只需付出最小的努力。
the full benefits of NDN with minimal efforts.
为了让物联网用户以最小的努力获得NDN的全部好处。
So we have two adaptation layers placed in our design.
因此，我们的设计中放置了两个适配层。
The first one is happening in the lower layer.
第一个发生在较低层。
It's actually just abstract the different link layer protocols.
它实际上只是抽象了不同的链路层协议。
And a rest the NDN interest and data packets into the link layer frames.
它将NDN的兴趣包和数据包封装进链路层帧中。
So basically it's transforming the name prefix to the interface mapping.
所以基本上是将名字前缀转换成接口映射。
And the other one is happening in the upper layer,
而另一个发生在上层，
which is actually doing the translation work is gonna translate
它实际上正在进行翻译工作的将会进行翻译
application level information to more meaningful data names for NDN.
应用层信息转换为NDN更有意义的数据名称。
After doing the Name Prefix transferring to the Data Mapping.
在进行名字前缀转换到数据映射之后。
So, here comes our Conclusion.
所以，我们来到了结论部分。
I'm not gonna read all of them but one thing that I wanna address is we're
我不打算全部阅读，但有一点我想要提出的是我们正在
currently working on the real simulation completion work based on the ndnSIM.
我们目前正在基于ndnSIM进行真实仿真完成工作。
And another underwater lower layer similar called the acquisition.
还有另一个类似的水下较低层，称为获取层。
We're still working on a simulation and
我们仍在进行一项模拟工作，
we would expect some results happening later this year.
我们预计今年晚些时候会有一些结果出现。
And we appreciate any comments, suggestions and
我们非常感谢任何评论、建议以及
also some help from the NDN community.
也得到了NDN社区的一些帮助。
And that's all for my presentation today.
这就是我今天演讲的全部内容。
Thanks.
谢谢。
>> Okay, thank you Qi.
好的，谢谢你，Qi。
We have a question from Kathy Nichols.
我们收到了Kathy Nichols的一个问题。
If you're sending commands via interest,
如果你通过兴趣发送指令，
doesn't that mean that you have to carefully target the interest since it's
这不就意味着你必须仔细地定位兴趣，因为它会
gonna be captured by the first node that can respond?
意味着它会被第一个能够响应的节点捕获？
>> Right, so that's true and like I said, we just simply borrow this
对，这是真的，就像我说的，我们只是简单地借鉴了这个
idea from the NDN like design because the interest can carry on the commands.
是的，这是真的，就像我说的，我们只是简单地借鉴了NDN（命名数据网络）的设计思想，因为兴趣包可以携带命令。但这是真的，我们需要谨慎使用这一点，因为
But that's true and we need to carefully use this because
但这是真的，我们需要谨慎使用这一点，因为
it's gonna be related to the security, yeah.
这将与安全有关，是的。
>> Sorry, Pawan has a question, how often do the sensors advertise the prefix?
>> 对不起，Pawan 有个问题，传感器有多频繁地广播前缀？
Do they do that every time new data is produced?
他们每次产生新数据都这样做吗？
And if not, then how does the consumer know of the new data production?
如果不是这样，那么消费者怎么知道新数据的产生呢？
>> Yeah, that's a good question.
是的，这是一个好问题。
It's actually totally depends on the kind of pre-configuration because we said,
实际上这完全取决于预配置的类型，因为我们说过，
in the underwater communication environments,
在水下通信环境中，
all those devices that actually the power hungry.
所有那些实际上非常耗电的设备。
So if we keep advertising whenever the data is available,
那么，如果我们一直在数据可用时进行广告推广，
then it's gonna be a nightmare for those devices.
那么，这对那些设备来说将会是一场噩梦。
So there could be different strategies in implementing this.
因此，在实施这一点时可能会有不同的策略。
So we actually what we want to do is, we can somehow
因此，我们实际上想要做的是，我们可以在某种程度上
develop some different policies depending on what type of devices.
根据不同类型的设备制定一些不同的策略。
What type of data is based on some priority stuff, to kind of
根据某些优先级事项来决定数据的类型。
distinguish different data immediate priority or try
区分不同数据的紧急优先级或尝试
to give the flexibility for the consumer and even the producer, yeah.
为消费者甚至生产者提供灵活性。
>> Okay, thanks.
好的，谢谢。
move on to the last speaker of the session which is Randall King.
我们现在转到本环节的最后一位演讲者，Randall King。
He is currently CTO of Operant Networks
他目前是Operant Networks的首席技术官。
a commercial startup that focuses on providing secure and
一家专注于提供安全且弹性通信的商业初创公司，服务于多种市场和行业。
resilient communications across a variety of markets and industries.
弹性通信服务覆盖了多种市场和行业。
His career is focused on technology transfer from academic and
他的职业生涯专注于将技术从学术界和行业研究人员转移到商业化引入和
industry researchers to commercial introduction and
行业研究人员到商业引进和
it's a pattern he hopes to recreate within the end.
他希望在最后重现这一模式。
After many years working on fiber optics and wireless communications at HP,
在惠普公司从事多年光纤和无线通信工作后，
he shifted his focus to renewable energy and
他将注意力转向了可再生能源，并且
helped build a successful solar industry startup.
帮助建立了一家成功的太阳能行业初创企业。
And Operant was formed by a team of people from those experiences and
Operant是由一群有着那些经历的人组成的团队。
is excited to be part of using NDN to transition our energy systems
对于使用NDN来过渡我们的能源系统成为其中的一部分感到兴奋。
to the cleaner, more resilient and secure smart grid of the future.
转向未来更清洁、更有弹性和更安全的智能电网。
So with that, I will hand it off to Randall.
那么，我就把话筒交给Randall。
>> Thanks, Kim.
谢谢，Kim。
Let me get the sharing going here.
让我开始共享屏幕。
So, I'm going to focus today on some work that we've done over the last year in
所以，我今天将主要介绍我们在过去一年中完成的一些工作。
collaboration between Operant Networks and Pollere Kathleen Nichols company.
合作之间的Operant Networks和Pollere Kathleen Nichols公司。
And the particular focus of this talk is how we were able to retrofit
这次演讲的特别重点是我们如何能够对现有的大型应用程序代码库进行改造，以便从NDN中获益。
a large existing application code base to benefit from NDN.
我们如何能够对现有的大型应用程序代码库进行改造，以便从NDN中获益。
And two reasonable questions you might have at this point would be why
在这一点上，您可能会有两个合理的疑问，那就是为什么
would we do this?
我们怎样做这件事？
And then how would we do this?
那么我们该如何做这件事呢？
And that's the questions I hope to answer by the end of the talk.
这些就是我希望在演讲结束时能回答的问题。
So, Operant, it's all about Commercializing NDN.
那么，操作者，这完全是关于商业化NDN的事情。
And I really enjoyed this morning's panel in the comments on what NDN needs next.
我今天早上真的很喜欢那个关于NDN接下来需要什么的讨论小组。
From our perspective, our CEO last night told me
从我们的角度来看，我们的CEO昨晚告诉我
what is needed is a real customer spending real money buying a real product.
所需的是一个真正的客户，用真金白银购买真正的产品。
And that's kind of what Operant's focused on finding that significant customer.
这正是Operant专注寻找的那种重要客户。
But whenever we talk to prospective customers, we have to tell them that NDN
但是每当我们与潜在客户交谈时，我们必须告诉他们NDN的运作方式与众不同，并开始讨论关于兴趣数据交换等事宜。
works differently and start talking about interest data exchanges and things.
运作方式与众不同，并开始讨论关于兴趣数据交换等事宜。
But in the context of introducing new technologies,
但在引入新技术的背景下，
we've now highlighted a barrier to adoption.
我们现在已经突出了一个采纳障碍。
Because customers don't want new they want better.
因为顾客不想要新的，他们想要更好的。
And so, in particular, to adopt the new technology,
因此，特别是要采用新技术，
they have to be strongly motivated.
他们必须有强烈的动力。
It can't be 10% better.
它不能只好上10%。
It's got to be 10 times better.
它必须要好上10倍。
So we've been learning over the last few years what
所以我们在过去几年里一直在了解什么
would be the motivators that would get people to switch to an NDN based solution.
将是促使人们转向基于NDN的解决方案的动因。
And these four kind of jump out.
这四种显得尤为突出。
The first is Security, which is super important to people.
第一是安全性，这对人们来说至关重要。
It's trending, everybody wants to talk about it, but
它正成为潮流，每个人都想谈论它，但是
it's very hard to quantify and value if monetarily.
它非常难以量化和用金钱来评估其价值。
Try to put a dollar value on security.
尝试对安全性进行金钱估值。
Multiparty communications, big thing I think but
多方通信，我认为这是个大事，但是
it's not common yet it's on the horizon and people want to talk about it but
它还不普遍，但它在地平线上，人们想要谈论它，但是
they're not buying solutions there nearly as much as I'd hoped.
他们在那里购买解决方案的程度远没有我希望的那么多。
Running Multiple physical layers in series or parallel.
在串联或并联中运行多个物理层。
It's a great capability of NDN but
NDN具有很强的能力，但是……
there's a lot of workarounds in industry to deal with these issues.
在工业中有很多解决这些问题的变通办法。
And Caching and data throughput, another great feature, but
缓存和数据吞吐量，又是一个很棒的特性，但是
large customers have solutions in place with legacy networking and
大型客户已经部署了基于传统网络的解决方案，
they're not strongly motivated yet to change.
他们目前还没有强烈的动力去做出改变。
So, we haven't found the lockout applications,
所以，我们还没有找到锁定应用程序，
the one where if you don't do it within the end, you just can't do it.
如果你不在最后期限之前完成，那你就无法完成了。
That's seems to be hard to find.
这似乎很难找到。
Instead, we've been finding ones that have like multiples of these parameters and
相反，我们发现的是具有这些参数多个倍数的。
motivators.
激励因素。
And one in particular I wanna talk about is intrusion detection systems,
特别要提到的一个是入侵检测系统，
which is something we got involved with about a year and a half ago.
这是我们大约一年半前开始参与的事情。
And just for a quick background, I'm sure everyone in this audience knows, but
这只是一个简单的背景介绍，我相信在场的每个人都知道，但是
most cyber protection tools are firewalls nowadays, protecting the network
大多数网络安全保护工具如今都是防火墙，用来保护网络。
parameters, generally looking at packet payloads as they traverse the perimeter.
参数通常是在数据包穿越网络边界时查看其有效载荷。
But the growth of encrypted traffic makes looking at these packets harder and
但是加密流量的增长使得查看这些数据包变得更加困难，
harder, I think,
更难了，我认为。
upwards of 70% of corporate network traffic is now encrypted.
超过70%的企业网络流量现在是加密的。
And the other thing is that sophisticated hackers get through perimeters eventually,
而且另一个问题是，精通技术的黑客最终总能突破网络边界。
it's just pretty much impossible thing to prevent.
这几乎是不可能防止的事情。
So intrusion detection systems or IDS, provide a supplement to firewalls and
因此，入侵检测系统或IDS，为防火墙提供了补充，并且
they're starting to generate a lot more interest.
他们开始引起了更多的兴趣。
The kind that we're looking at, they look at TCP/IP packet headers and
我们所研究的那种，它们会检查TCP/IP数据包的头部信息并且
they watch the traffic flow patterns and they look for anomalies.
它们监控流量模式并寻找异常情况。
And they're particularly valuable, because hackers,
它们特别有价值，因为黑客，
once they get through a large campus or a military base perimeter, they lurk.
一旦他们渗透进大型校园或军事基地的边界，他们就会潜伏下来。
They typically spend upwards of a month,
他们通常会花费超过一个月的时间，
the sophisticated hackers sit inside networks before they really attack.
这些精通技术的黑客在真正发起攻击之前，通常会潜伏在网络中一段时间。
They're looking for the vulnerabilities.
他们在寻找漏洞。
So if you distribute traffic sensors around your campus and
所以如果你在你的校园周围分布交通传感器并且
you watch the internal flows, you can learn a lot about what's going on.
如果你观察内部流动，你可以了解到很多正在发生的事情。
One of the Air Force people we work with told me that the mess hall should not
我们合作的一位空军人员告诉我，食堂不应该
be talking to the radar dome, and I think that's a good way to visualize this.
应该与雷达罩进行对话，我认为这是一个很好的形象化表达。
So, intrusion detection systems in particular distributed ones
因此，特别是分布式的入侵检测系统，
are an area where we think we could bring some of the benefits of NDN to light.
因此，特别是分布式的入侵检测系统，是一个我们认为可以展示NDN一些好处的领域。因为它结合了对高安全性的需求，因为这些观察网络，
Because it combines the need for high security because these watching networks,
因为它结合了对高安全性的需求，因为这些观察网络，
the IDS of sensors that are spread through the campus communicate with each other to
这些分布在校园各处的传感器的入侵检测系统（IDS）相互通信，以协作检测流量异常并向数据分析服务器提供数据。
collaborate on detecting flow anomalies and to provide data-to-analysis servers.
协作检测流量异常并向数据分析服务器提供数据。
They have to be much more secure than the network they're watching.
他们必须比他们监控的网络更加安全。
Otherwise, what good is it if the person that has hacked your network and
否则，如果有人黑进了你的网络而你却不知情，那又有什么用呢？
they can stop the IDS, you haven't really provided any value.
它们可以停止入侵检测系统，但你实际上并没有提供任何价值。
And you can see that that's also a multi-party communication thing,
你可以看到这也是一个多方通信的事情，
meaning many distributed sensors.
意味着许多分布式传感器。
And it can use multicast to its benefit.
它可以利用多播来获益。
So it's got a lot of motivators I mentioned on the previous slide.
所以它有很多我在前一张幻灯片上提到的动机因素。
And we pitched this at the Air Force and Department of Energy and
我们向空军和能源部提出了这个想法，
they agreed independently and they both funded an Indian based distributed
他们分别同意了，并且都资助了一个基于印度的分布式
intrusion detection system which we've been working for about a year on.
入侵检测系统，我们已经研究了大约一年时间。
And this is where you start thinking about how do you introduce a product.
这就是你开始思考如何推出一款产品的地方。
And so customers don't buy networking, they buy full solutions.
因此客户不仅仅购买网络设备，他们购买的是完整的解决方案。
In one of the markets we investigated, a customer told us that there's an 18 to 1
在我们调查的一个市场中，一位客户告诉我们，他们在完整解决方案和
ratio between what they pay on a full solution and
他们在完整解决方案上的支出与
So if you just sell connectivity, you're only looking at providing 5% of
所以如果你只是出售连接服务，你只关注于提供5%的
the value and that doesn't motivate a commercial company.
价值，这并不能激励一家商业公司。
But in the cybersecurity space, there's an opportunity for
但在网络安全领域，存在一个机会，
us because it's a really robust community of tools.
因为这里有一个非常强大的工具社区。
There's the very complex landscape of commercially and technically,
这里有一个商业上和技术上非常复杂的格局，
and a lot of people playing in collaborative tools,
还有很多人在使用协作工具进行合作。
and in particular, there's a robust open source community.
特别是存在一个强大的开源社区。
And that's how we got involved,
我们就是这样参与进来的，
was we were leveraging something called Zeek which was previously called Bro,
我们利用的是一个名为Zeek的系统，它之前被称作Bro，
which is an open source based system that's been worked on for decades now.
这是一个基于开源的系统，经过了几十年的发展。
And it's inherently distributed.
它本质上是分布式的。
It's a sensor based system that does the kinds of things I've talked about
它是一个基于传感器的系统，能够执行我之前谈论过的那些功能。
previously.
之前。
It pre-processes network traffic flow, and creates logs and
它预处理网络流量，并创建日志和
alerts that you can use to look for intrusion.
它会生成您可以用来检测入侵的警报。
And Zeek has already in place of broker based pub sub communications framework.
Zeek已经实现了基于代理的发布/订阅通信框架。
It uses the TCP/IP type security in order to connect
它使用TCP/IP类型的安全性来进行连接。
multiple machines and multiple instances.
多台机器和多个实例。
And what we did was we were placed that TCP based broker pub/sub
我们所做的就是我们放置了基于TCP的代理发布/订阅系统。
with an Indian secure NBN base broker list pub/sub transport.
我们使用了一个基于印度安全NBN基础的代理列表发布/订阅传输方式。
So we took 90% of the value in the existing Zeek world and
因此，我们保留了现有Zeek世界90%的价值，并且……
we enhanced it by adding NDN communications stuff.
因此，我们通过增加NDN通信组件来对其进行了增强。
And if you think about how you would build a secure pub sub in a TCP/IP world,
如果你考虑在一个TCP/IP的世界里如何构建一个安全的发布/订阅系统，
there's kind of two solutions that come to mind.
有两种解决方案浮现在我脑海中。
One is MQTT, which I'm sure most people are familiar with.
一种是MQTT，我相信大多数人都熟悉。
It's very lightweight TCP protocol, mostly for IoT.
它是一种非常轻量级的TCP协议，主要用于物联网。
It's got a broker, so there's some central node, sometimes they're broken
它具有一个代理，所以有一个中央节点，有时这些节点会出现故障。
up into multiples, but there's always this concept of someone who knows where all
分成多个部分，但总有一个概念，即有人知道所有的位置。
the devices are in an IP space, and the topics and messages that get published.
设备位于一个IP空间内，并且会发布主题和消息。
And that broker is a target for cyber attack and
这个代理是网络攻击的目标，并且
it's the single point of failure and it's really not perfect.
它是单点故障的源头，而且确实不完美。
MQTT doesn't inherently bring security you
MQTT本身并不内置安全性特性，你
have to provide that in a TLS type approach.
必须采用类似TLS的方法来提供这种安全性。
There is a solution on the market that's more aimed at this kind of thing
市场上有一种解决方案更专注于这类事务。
called DDS, and it's data distribution service.
它被称为DDS，即数据分发服务。
And it really does a lot of the things that you'd want a secure pub sub to do.
它确实完成了很多你希望一个安全的发布/订阅系统所能做的事情。
But basically all node addresses and
但基本上所有节点地址和
subscribed topics have to be stored within every node because there's no broker.
订阅的主题必须存储在每个节点中，因为没有代理。
And that's very difficult because nodes are continually
而这非常困难，因为节点在不断地
trying to learn about other nodes and keep track of pub sub and all this, and
试图了解其他节点并跟踪发布/订阅等所有这些内容，以及
it's just way too much overload to the network.
它对网络的负载实在是太大了。
And when you use it in any kind of application that has limited bandwidth,
当你在任何带宽有限的应用中使用它时，
you find out pretty quick that it's just not efficient enough to do all
你很快就会发现，在任何带宽有限的应用中使用它时，它的效率还是不够高，无法完成所有的 that overhead.
that overhead.
因此，我们所做的是，我会很快跳过这部分，
first of all, because Kathy Nichols did most of the work underneath this, and
首先，因为Kathy Nichols完成了这项工作的大部分底层工作，还有
second of all, because she's already provided quite a bit of information and
其次，因为她已经提供了相当多的信息，
I referenced a link there.
我在那里引用了一个链接。
But last fall, at the ACM conference, she presented on a work called DNMP,
但去年秋天，在ACM会议上，她展示了一个名为DNMP的工作，
which involved the idea of a bespoke transport.
这涉及到了一个定制运输的概念。
And what that is, is its a set of tools that is a collection
这实际上是一套工具，是一个集合
of modules that implement an NDN transport, and
它由实现NDN传输的模块组成，并且
it allows you to adapt it to specific needs.
它允许你根据特定需求进行调整。
And so what we did with it working with her was to build a message based pub sub,
于是我们与她合作所做的就是构建了一个基于消息的发布/订阅系统，
that allows us to basically use the same module she'd already developed.
这使我们能够基本上使用她已经开发的相同模块。
And put an MQTT like API on so that we now have this
并在此基础上实现了一个类似MQTT的API，这样我们现在就拥有了这个功能。
secure broker lists pub/sub based on sync, and
基于同步的安全代理服务器列表支持发布/订阅模式，并且
it can work directly with the Zeek application.
它可以直接与Zeek应用程序一起工作。
Embedded within that approach is the versec toolkit that
嵌入在那种方法中的是versec工具包，它
Ben Jacobson's been working on.
本·雅各布森一直在研究的。
And this is going to be a way where trust schemas that
这将是一种方式，信任模式可以……
apply to the publication's within the transport
应用于传输层内的出版物。
layer are able to be controlled by complex trust rules.
层可以通过复杂的信任规则来控制。
And those trust rules are deployed in the form of a sign trust scheme binary, so
那些信任规则以签名信任方案二进制的形式部署，所以
they can use all the inherent advantages of distribution in NDN.
它们可以利用NDN中分布式的所有内在优势。
>> Presents in order to update and move trust schemas around
>> 为了更新和移动信任模式，提供了相应的方法。
out of all of that we've built something called Sentinel.
在所有这些基础上，我们构建了一个被称为Sentinel的系统。
And I'm not gonna try to walk through all of these different boxes, but
我不打算尝试逐一解释所有这些不同的方框，但是
the idea of this is that it it drops into the red box which is the Zeke manager.
这个想法是它会落入红色的方框中，那就是Zeke管理器。
It's an instance of Zeke that has a special role.
它是一个具有特殊角色的Zeke实例。
There's roles like I mentioned in Zeke for different distributed nodes.
它在Zeke中有我提到的不同分布式节点的特殊角色。
And the existing Zeke messages use this blue box, the Sentinel
而现有的Zeke消息使用这个蓝色盒子，即Sentinel。
bespoke transport as a Pub/Sub with the embedded Versa trust system and
定制传输作为具有嵌入式Versa信任系统的发布/订阅服务，以及
it can basically replace the piece of Zeke that was using TCP/IP.
它基本上可以替代之前使用TCP/IP的Zeke部分。
So this has been a successful project.
所以这是一个成功的项目。
We've been able to get this functioning in something like a year.
我们已经能够在大约一年的时间里让这个项目运作起来。
I wanna highlight one more aspect,
我想再强调一个方面，
which is that it's based on something we're calling NDN-IND.
这就是它基于我们所说的NDN-IND。
IND in this context stands for industrial, because what we wanna
在这个上下文中，IND代表工业，因为我们想要的是
do is take the NDN community into a space that where industrial users
将NDN社区带入一个工业用户所在的空间，
will have a standardized, simplified, invalidated NDN platform.
将拥有一个标准化、简化、失效的NDN平台。
We now have repose for NDN-IND we're going to be
我们现在已经为NDN-IND找到了解决方案，我们将会
exposing those this year to the NDN community represented by this group.
暴露这些问题于今年，面向由此群体代表的NDN社区。
They're being reviewed under some of our grant work by national labs,
它们正在由国家实验室审查，作为我们某些资助工作的一部分，
such as India and National Renewable Energy labs.
它们正在由国家实验室审查，作为我们某些资助工作的一部分，比如印度和国家可再生能源实验室。I'm happy to talk to anyone about it more and
I'm happy to talk to anyone about it more and
我很乐意进一步与任何人讨论这个话题。
we'll be distributing more information during this next year.
我们将在明年分发更多信息。
Our hope is that the next time we come here, we'll be rolling this out to more of
我们希望下一次我们来到这里时，能够将这个推广给更多的...
a commercial audience and doing like press releases and
一个商业受众，并进行新闻发布会等活动。
a more publicity oriented method to get in the outliner.
一种更以宣传为导向的方法来吸引边缘受众。
And for instance, this could provide some of the use for
例如，这可能为一些用途提供帮助，
other members of industry, but it could also provide a stable platform for
其他行业成员，但它也可以为
people like the hackers that Jeff Burke was talking about this morning.
像Jeff Burke今天早上谈到的那些黑客。
We made some specific changes to NDN-IND for Sentinel and it was sort of an example
我们对NDN-IND进行了一些针对Sentinel的具体更改，这在某种程度上是一个例子。
of how we're going to move it forward carefully, and in small steps.
我们将谨慎且循序渐进地推进它的发展。
For instance, we're adding AEAD encryption as an option,
例如，我们正在添加AEAD加密作为一种选择，
because we feel that's a step forward that NDN could use in industrial setting.
因为我们认为这是NDN在工业环境中可以使用的一个进步。
So in summary, we've implemented the Sentinel IDS using
因此，总结来说，我们已经使用Sentinel IDS实现了
the the broker-less NDN pub/sub based on Cathy's bespoke transport.
我们在Cathy定制的传输基础上实现了无代理的NDN发布/订阅系统。
We've built Sims on top of that the user interfaces specifically for
我们在此基础上构建了Sims，专门为用户界面设计。
the Air Force and for the solar markets, two separate interfaces.
我们为空军和太阳能市场构建了两个不同的界面。
And this demonstrates some method of
这展示了一种方法
retrofitting an existing complex application within the end.
在最后对现有的复杂应用程序进行改造。
But within a commercially viable effort level,
但在商业上可行的努力范围内，
we didn't have to rewrite all of the code that Zeke provides.
我们不需要重写Zeke提供的所有代码。
As a next step, we're going to be looking at the other possible MQTT applications,
作为下一步，我们将考察其他可能的MQTT应用。
ecause we have this pub/sub now and it could pretty easily drop into places that
由于我们现在有了这种发布/订阅机制，它可以很容易地嵌入到可能需要使用MQTT的场合，但是不需要经纪人且更加安全。
expect to use MQTT, but broker-less and more secure.
期望使用MQTT，但无需经纪人且更加安全。
And then our real focus over the next year will be applying
接下来的一年，我们真正的重点将是应用这些技术于公用事业通信。
some of these technologies to utility communications.
将这些技术应用于公用事业通信。
And when I come back next year,
当我明年回来时，
I hope to be able to report even more exciting results in that area.
我希望能在那个领域报告更加激动人心的成果。
Thanks.
谢谢。
>> Okay, thanks Randy.
>> 好的，谢谢兰迪。
I have a quick clarification question.
我有一个简短的澄清问题。
Could you say I'm sorry if I missed it, what SIEMs?
如果我错过了，你能说我很抱歉吗？是哪些SIEMs？
>> You're putting me on the spot.
你让我为难了。
It's a security information and event manager, maybe.
它可能是一个安全信息和事件管理器。
>> Okay.
好的。
>> It's basically a GUI that allows people to use it in their world to look for
>> 它基本上是一个图形用户界面，允许人们在他们的世界中使用它来寻找
intrusions, this black box on the screen as a SIEM.
它基本上是一个图形用户界面，允许人们在他们的世界中使用它来寻找入侵，这个屏幕上的黑盒子作为一个安全信息和事件管理(SIEM)系统。
>> I see, okay, cool.
我明白了，好的，很酷。
Any questions?
有什么问题吗？
So do you anticipate?
那么你预期吗？
So you're developing this for sort of specific markets and
所以你是为特定市场开发这个产品吗？
I actually would be interested in hearing more about the security review
我实际上很想了解更多关于安全审查的信息。
that's going on, but my question would be do you see this going to other?
实际上正在发生的情况是什么，但我的问题是，你认为这会扩展到其他领域吗？
You mentioned the energy industry, do you think this
您提到了能源行业，您认为这会
will be sort of do you anticipate that you will have to
对其他类别的应用程序进行改变吗？
>> Well, I think that's sort of the nature of this bespoke transport approach,
嗯，我认为这就是这种定制运输方法的本质。
which is that you have Cathy's separated out application specific SIEMs
这就是你有了凯西分离出来的针对特定应用的SIEMs。
that provide a fairly limited environment that needs change to that,
这提供了一个相当有限的环境，需要对此进行改变，
of course, to be in the air.
当然是要在空中。
You really want some application knowledge built-in.
你真的想要一些内置的应用知识。
And so It's kind of a just enough change,
所以这种变化恰到好处，
I think is the way we're looking at it free application.
我认为这是我们认为它是免费应用程序的方式。
>> Yeah, that's a great answer.
是的，这是一个很好的回答。
Okay, well, thank you very much.
好的，非常感谢您。
Very interesting talks, please all four speakers.
非常有趣的演讲，请四位演讲者上台。
Imagine a rousing round of applause for your talks and thank you.
想象一下，为你们的演讲响起一阵热烈的掌声，谢谢你们。
And with that, I'll hand it back to Lotfi.
接下来，我将把话筒交回给洛特菲。
>> Thank you very much, Ken.
>> 非常感谢你，肯。
Now is the last break.
现在是最后一个休息时间。
We're supposed to be back at 3:30.
我们应该在3点半回来。
So let's stick to that.
那我们就这样定了。
You all back at 3:30.
你们都在3:30回来。
Thank you.
谢谢。